<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Gender Bias with R</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-gender-bias-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analyzing-gender-bias-with-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our October event, R-Ladies Yipeng Lai and Stacy Lansey will share short talks on using R for analyzing gender bias on Wikipedia and learning R through data visualization (which motivated an interesting side project on gender).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda-times-approximate&#34;&gt;Agenda (times approximate):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Text Analysis in R: Gender Bias in Wikipedia Biographies&amp;rdquo; by Yipeng Lai
7:30-7:55: &amp;ldquo;R is for Resilience: Learning R through Data Visualization&amp;rdquo; by Stacy Lansey
7:55-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-abstracts&#34;&gt;Talk Abstracts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Text Analysis in R: Gender Bias in Wikipedia Biographies&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Yipeng Lai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: This talk will focus on how to manipulate and analyze textual data in R using the quanteda​ package. Yipeng will go over some basic natural language processing techniques. She will talk you through how to apply these techniques to dissect gender bias in Wikipedia biographies. She finds that biographies about female subjects are more likely to contain terms relating to gender and marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Yipeng is an Applied Scientist at StreetEasy, NYC&amp;rsquo;s local real estate marketplace. She just received her MS in Data Science from New York University this summer. She is passionate about natural language processing, data science for social good, and urban data. When she is not working with data, you can find her blogging about food and practicing latte art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;R is for Resilience: Learning R through Data Visualization&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Stacy Lansey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: I will talk about my first R Project, the visualizations for the Warby Parker Impact Report, and how I used the skills I gained to advocate for a shift in the descriptive adjectives associated with female students at my son&amp;rsquo;s school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Stacy Lansey is the Data Science Analyst at Warby Parker. She came to this role from a background in real estate and finance and is speaking about her experiences learning R in this role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/273937932/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-charts-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-charts-lie/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our September book club, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing &amp;ldquo;How Charts Lie: Getting Smarter about Visual Information&amp;rdquo; by Alberto Cairo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoom link will be available to attendees on the Meetup event page as of 9 am Eastern on September 26th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/272943459/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies NYC Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks-2020/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are hosting a very special event - lightning talks from the R-Ladies community! Come out to hear a variety of R and Data Science talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:05: Welcome and R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:05-8:30: Lightning Talks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talks-and-speakers&#34;&gt;Talks and Speakers:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Partial Correlation Networks in R&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Erin McDonnell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Batch Production of Reports in RMarkdown&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Alyssa Goldberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time Series Analysis of Bird Migrations Above NYC Skies Using bioRad&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Mei Guan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Webscraping with &amp;lsquo;rvest&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Anisha BharathSingh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Intro to Latent Variable Modeling&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Apoorva Srinivasan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Automating Reports with Gmailr&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Samantha Emanuele&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to create a bookdown book in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Joyce Robbins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Model Explainability and Interpretability&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Isabel Zimmerman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Website Checkout Funnel Analysis in R&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Christina Kim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &amp;lsquo;comorbidity&amp;rsquo; package&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yolanda Barrón&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using Google Trends data to assess the impact of COVID-19 on suicidality and suicide - risk factors&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Emily Halford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Melvin: a DL-based companion bot&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; MaryLena Bleile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/272069781/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies NYC networking social event</title>
      <link>/post/networking-social-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/networking-social-event/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Though we&amp;rsquo;ll be remote at least through the end of 2020, R-Ladies NYC doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to lose the magic of meetups, where we get to network, socialize, meet new people, and make connections. For our August meetup, we&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting a networking social event where we&amp;rsquo;ll utilize breakout rooms to allow participants to connect (or re-connect) with other members of our community in smaller groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10: Welcome and R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-8:30: Breakout room chats (3-5 people, and we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some topics if that helps!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/272538491/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Authors of &#34;Build a Career in Data Science&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/q-a-authors-build-a-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/q-a-authors-build-a-career/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Authors of &amp;ldquo;Build a Career in Data Science&amp;rdquo; Emily Robinson and Jacqueline Nolis will read selections from their book and discuss why they were meaningful and what thinking went into making it. In this session you’ll learn about some of the higher-level thinking that went into designing a book to help people excel in their data science careers, as well as hear stories from Emily and Jacqueline’s pasts that ended up shaping the narrative. After Emily and Jacqueline discuss their book, the floor will open so anyone can ask their data science career questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:05-7:40: Emily &amp;amp; Jacqueline talk about their book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:40-8:15: Audience Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:15-8:20: Wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-bios&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Bios&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Robinson is a senior data scientist at Warby Parker, where she works on a centralized team tackling some of the company&amp;rsquo;s projects. She previously worked at DataCamp, where she built and ran their experimentation analytics system, and at Etsy, where she worked with their search team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Jacqueline Nolis is a principal data scientist at Brightloom where she creates models to help restaurants and retailers improve the customer experience. She has a PhD in Industrial Engineering, and has over a decade of experience with helping companies use data, ranking from DSW to Airbnb. For fun Jacqueline likes to use data science for humor—like using deep learning to generate offensive license plates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/271928063/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leading R Trainings &amp; Prototyping with flexdashboards</title>
      <link>/post/leading-trainings-prototyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/leading-trainings-prototyping/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our very own R-Ladies NYC board members Erin Grand and Kaelen Medeiros will give two short talks this month on leading R trainings for coworkers and flexdashboard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Leading R Trainings for Coworkers&amp;rdquo; by Erin Grand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30-7:55: &amp;ldquo;flexdashboard for Prototyping and Profit&amp;rdquo; by Kaelen Medeiros&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-leading-r-trainings-for-coworkers&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Leading R Trainings for Coworkers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-erin-grand&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Erin Grand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Erin has lead a set of 6+ R trainings for her coworkers ranging from &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Tidyverse&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Using SQL and R Together.&amp;rdquo; Leading such trainings, while using many of the same teaching skills, offer different challenges from teaching in a workshop or classroom setting. Erin will discuss the Why&amp;rsquo;s, How&amp;rsquo;s, and Best Practices she&amp;rsquo;s learned over the past few years of leading trainings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Erin works as a Data Scientist at Uncommon Schools where she trains coworkers in R as well as maintaining two R packages. Prior to Uncommon, she worked as a Data Scientist at Crisis Text Line, and a software programmer at NASA while completing her Data Science Masters at Columbia University. Before data science, Erin researched star formation and taught introductory courses in astronomy and physics at the University of Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-flexdashboard-for-prototyping-and-profit&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; flexdashboard for Prototyping and Profit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-kaelen-medeiros&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaelen Medeiros&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The flexdashboard package allows you to build Shiny dashboards quickly using a RMarkdown document. This is advantageous in situations where you need to prototype a data product (often a dashboard or interactive report) and need to sell stakeholders on the value of the product built. Kaelen will talk about the basics of using flexdashboard and then give tips on utilizing it to build data product MVPs (minimum viable products) to communicate vision to stakeholders, plus discuss flexdashboard extensions and how to go about converting your flexdash to a Shiny dashboard (if you&amp;rsquo;re ready or even need to!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaelen is a data scientist at Medidata Solutions where they work as an R programmer on the microservices team. They&amp;rsquo;ve also worked at Spring Health, DataCamp, HERE Technologies, and have done a fair amount of R and Shiny consulting on the side. Kaelen was at various times a film theorist, preschool teacher, test prep tutor, videographer, and nanny before getting a MS in biostatistics from LSU Health Sciences Center in 2016 and starting to work as a statistician and data scientist. They have a cat named Scully and enjoy talking about podcats, aliens, data, and would love to see a photo of your pet if you&amp;rsquo;re sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/271374747/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mappy Hour with R-Ladies: Spatial Data Analysis in R</title>
      <link>/post/mappy-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mappy-hour/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our very own Ayanthi Gunawardana and R-Ladies Chicago board member Angela Li join us this month to talk spatial statistics in R!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and a link will be sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Uncharted Territory: An Introduction to Making Clear and Accurate Maps&amp;rdquo; by Ayanthi Gunawardana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30-7:55: &amp;ldquo;How to Be a Resilient Geospatial R useR: First Steps, Learning More, and the Spatial R-Ladies Community&amp;rdquo; by Angela Li&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-uncharted-territory-an-introduction-to-making-clear-and-accurate-maps&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Uncharted Territory: An Introduction to Making Clear and Accurate Maps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-ayanthi-gunawardana&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Ayanthi Gunawardana&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Over the course of a decade, maps have gone from folded paper booklets inside the glove compartment of a car to having a map of the entire world inside everyone’s smartphone. As more spatial data becomes available, maps are no longer simple representations of places on Earth; maps now include visualizations of a wide range of newly available spatial datasets. We collect more and more data with location information, but does this mean that this information belongs on a map? I will cover some basic principles of good cartography and what to keep in mind when creating a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Ayanthi is a Data and Research Analyst at the New York City Department of Transportation, where she analyzes car crash data to inform street safety projects and street redesign. Ayanthi has a Masters in City and Regional Planning from Rutgers University, which sparked her interest in maps and data. When she&amp;rsquo;s not looking at maps, you can find Ayanthi at Brazilian Jiu Jitsu class (pre pandemic) or cooking something spicy (all the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-how-to-be-a-resilient-geospatial-r-user-first-steps-learning-more-and-the-spatial-r-ladies-community&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; How to Be a Resilient Geospatial R useR: First Steps, Learning More, and the Spatial R-Ladies Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-angela-li&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Angela Li&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning to work with geospatial data in R can be challenging, but the right resources and open-source community can help whether you’re starting out with spatial data or moving your spatial analysis workflow to R. I’ll cover how you can get started with geospatial analysis in R, common questions and challenges I’ve seen, and where you can turn when you get stuck. I’ll draw insights from my experiences working 1-on-1 with researchers, teaching and assisting with spatial R workshops, and fielding questions from the #rspatialchat Twitter hashtag. Finally, I’ll discuss next steps for R-Ladies in the #rspatial community and talk about how we can help each other become better spatial data practitioners together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Angela is a researcher and the R Spatial Advocate at the Center for Spatial Data Science at the University of Chicago. She has a background in spatial analysis, econometrics, and public policy. Prior to her current position, she worked at a startup focused on mobility and conducted research on housing and demolition in Detroit. She is currently researching the opioid epidemic in America, working with public health experts to better understand access to treatment. She is passionate about creating opportunities for underrepresented minorities to advance their data science and spatial thinking skills, starting R-Ladies Chicago and the #rspatialchat hashtag on Twitter, among other projects. She is a huge fan of the New York Times crossword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angela’s website is &lt;a href=&#34;angela-li.github.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;angela-li.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find her on Github at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angela-li&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@angela-li&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CivicAngela&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@CivicAngela&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/270611485/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Blogs</title>
      <link>/post/all-about-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/all-about-blogs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re so excited to have Angeline, Anisha, Emily, and Sharla talk about their experience with sharing their work through blog posts and twitter! Please email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nyc@rladies.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nyc@rladies.org&lt;/a&gt; with your question(s) for our amazing panelists to address, or submit them below in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom. A link will be sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;panelist-bios&#34;&gt;Panelist Bios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;emily-robinson&#34;&gt;Emily Robinson&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Robinson&lt;/strong&gt; is a senior data scientist at Warby Parker, where she works on a centralized team tackling some of the company’s biggest projects. She is the author of the book &lt;a href=&#34;datascicareer.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Build a Career in Data Science&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, a guide to all the non-technical skills and knowledge you need to get into and succeed in data science, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jnolis.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jacqueline Nolis&lt;/a&gt;. She regularly gives talks and writes on her blog, &lt;a href=&#34;hookedondata.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hookedondata.org&lt;/a&gt;, about A/B testing, programming in R, career advice, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily&amp;rsquo;s website is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hookedondata.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://hookedondata.org&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find her on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robinsones&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/robinson_es&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anisha-bharathsingh&#34;&gt;Anisha BharathSingh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anisha BharathSingh&lt;/strong&gt; is currently an SEO Analyst at Omnicom Media Group, with over 2.5 years in Digital Marketing. Last year, she started learning R in order to improve her data skills and learn about data science. In addition to that, she started a blog to showcase the data + R skills that she has been learning along with writing about data-related Meetups and books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anisha&amp;rsquo;s blog is &lt;a href=&#34;https://journeytodatascientist.blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://journeytodatascientist.blog/&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find her on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnishaB95&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thesparemoments&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;angeline-protacio&#34;&gt;Angeline Protacio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angeline&lt;/strong&gt; is a data scientist at Protacio Analytics LLC, consulting on projects spanning different disciplines. She is currently growing her data science expertise through the data science bootcamp program at Metis. Her background is in epidemiology and genetics and has experience working with data relating to mental health, breast cancer risk, and environmental risk factors. She spends her free time trying to win at fantasy baseball (with data) and practicing French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angeline&amp;rsquo;s website is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.angelineprotacio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.angelineprotacio.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find her on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angelinepro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dataangeline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sharla-gelfand&#34;&gt;Sharla Gelfand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharla Gelfand&lt;/strong&gt; is a freelance R developer focusing on package development and reproducible reporting workflows. She is a long-time R user and co-organizer of the Toronto R-Ladies chapter and frequently shares old and new favourite #rstats functions via the hashtag #TwoFunctionsMostDays on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharla&amp;rsquo;s blog is &lt;a href=&#34;https://sharla.party&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://sharla.party&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find her on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sharlagelfand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sharlagelfand&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/270210924/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for self-guided learning</title>
      <link>/post/resources-for-self-guided-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/resources-for-self-guided-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As New Yorkers do all we can to stay well in the times of coronavirus, all of our routines have changed. For some of us, this may mean more time devoted to strengthening our data skills. If this is you, here is a collection of resources that can get you up and running with learning a new skill in R. These were originally compiled for the R-Ladies NYC Code-llaboration Hangout back in January, and are organized by topic: &lt;a href=&#34;#tidy-tuesday&#34;&gt;Tidy Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#building-a-package&#34;&gt;Building a Package&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#building-a-website&#34;&gt;Building a Website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#forecasting-and-time-series-analysis&#34;&gt;Time Series Analysis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#everything-else&#34;&gt;Everything Else&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tidy-tuesday&#34;&gt;Tidy Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction, guidelines and datasets: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Official Repo for the #tidytuesday project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; book on how to transform and visualize data with R: &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides from Luda Janda’s ggplot talk at the NYC Open Statistical Programming Meetup: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githack.com/ljanda/nyhackr_talk_2019_09_19/master/ny_hackr_talk_2019_09_19.html#1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the ggplot glow-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other dataviz and ggplot resources:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datacarpentry.org/R-ecology-lesson/04-visualization-ggplot2.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data carpentry&amp;rsquo;s Data Visualization with ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://r-statistics.co/ggplot2-Tutorial-With-R.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to make any plot in ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-package&#34;&gt;Building a Package&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;http://raw.githack.com/Seborinos/rladiesnyc_package_workshop/master/rladiesnyc_package_workshop.html#1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slides from Sebastian Teran Hidalgo’s R-Ladies talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other resources:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-mageddon.netlify.com/post/writing-an-r-package-from-scratch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Another tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://r-pkgs.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s book on R packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/roxygen2/vignettes/roxygen2.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Understanding roxygen2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About writing good functions

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat545.com/functions-part1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jenny Byran&amp;rsquo;s wisdom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/functions.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Functions in Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://swcarpentry.github.io/r-novice-inflammation/02-func-R/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creating Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-website&#34;&gt;Building a Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.storybench.org/how-to-build-a-website-with-blogdown-in-r/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to build a website with Blogdown in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other resources:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;THE&lt;/em&gt; book about blogdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/2019-03-04-hugo-troubleshooting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Excellent troubleshooting tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emilyzabor.com/tutorials/rmarkdown_websites_tutorial.html#personal_website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Another way of building websites with r (with rmarkdown and github hosting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional reference by Alison Hill:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/2017-06-12-up-and-running-with-blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Up &amp;amp; Running with blogdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/2019-02-21-hugo-page-bundles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Spoonful of Hugo: Page Bundles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/2019-02-19-hugo-netlify-toml/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Spoonful of Hugo: The netlify.toml File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/post/2019-02-19-hugo-archetypes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Spoonful of Hugo: Archetypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;forecasting-and-time-series-analysis&#34;&gt;Forecasting and Time Series Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro to Time Series Forecasting ARIMA Modeling:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2015/12/complete-tutorial-time-series-modeling/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Complete Tutorial on Time Series Modeling in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pluralsight.com/guides/time-series-forecasting-using-r&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Time Series Forecasting Using R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://r-statistics.co/Time-Series-Forecasting-With-R.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Time Series Forecasting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a-little-book-of-r-for-time-series.readthedocs.io/en/latest/src/timeseries.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using R for Time Series Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/web-traffic-time-series-forecasting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Test out your skills with this Kaggle competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://otexts.com/fpp3/tsibble-objects.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tsibble Objects&lt;/a&gt; (bonus link, thanks Emily Robinson!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;everything-else&#34;&gt;Everything Else&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting started:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat545.com/install.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jenny Bryan&amp;rsquo;s class on &lt;em&gt;Data wrangling, exploration, and analysis with R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hadley Wickham &amp;amp; Garrett Grolemund&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourcodingclub.github.io/2016/11/13/intro-to-r.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Getting Started with R and RStiudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://happygitwithr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working with Git and github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maps

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/tmap/vignettes/tmap-getstarted.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;With tmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.littlemissdata.com/blog/maps&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;With Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.github.io/leaflet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;With leaflet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>timetrackR and gtsummary</title>
      <link>/post/timetrackr-and-gtsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/timetrackr-and-gtsummary/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our speakers for the night will be Jessica Lavery and Margie Hannum from Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center. Jessica will be talking about the timetrackR app. Margie will be discussing the gtsummary package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:55 pm Introductions and Social Time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7 pm R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10 Sponsor Message from IBM Developer New York&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-7:40 It&amp;rsquo;s Time to Shine with timetrackR App, Jessica Lavery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:40-8:10 Creating publication-ready and reproducible analytical tables with gtsummary, Margie Hannum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:10-8:30 Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-it-s-time-to-shine-with-the-timetrackr-app&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s Time to Shine with the timetrackR App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-jessica-lavery&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Jessica Lavery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; While tracking time may seem like a mundane task that in and of itself consumes your time, if monitored and assessed regularly it can be useful to create a record of your work and to identify potential areas for improving efficiency. The timetrackR Shiny app provides a high-level summary of active, inactive and upcoming projects, as well as visualizations for the percentage of time spent by project or project investigator, number of hours spent on each project, and a timeline framing each project’s trajectory from planning through analysis and manuscript preparation. With the option to filter by year, investigator and analyst, the app is versatile enough to use for an individual or for an entire team as well as for use on a regular basis and for year-end or longer-term reviews of how time was spent. I will highlight the key features of the app and demonstrate how to integrate into your current workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Jessica Lavery is a Biostatistician in the Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center. She has an MS in Biostatistics from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (2014) and as of Fall 2019 is also pursuing a doctorate in public health (DrPH) in Biostatistics at Columbia University. Her research focuses primarily on retrospective analyses using institutional and claims data sources. She also serves as the[masked] Volunteer Coordinator for the Caucus for Women in Statistics. Follow her on Twitter @jessicalavs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-creating-publication-ready-and-reproducible-analytical-tables-with-gtsummary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Creating publication-ready and reproducible analytical tables with gtsummary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenter-margie-hannum&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Margie Hannum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; A critical aspect of many data analysis projects is presenting tables of summary statistics and regression model results. However, summarizing results into publication-ready tables often requires a lot of extra code to customize (e.g. create reference line for categorical variables, format p-values a certain way, bold variable labels, merge multiple model results into one table, etc.). The {gtsummary} package provides an elegant and flexible way to make summary and analytic tables in R. Written as a companion to the {gt} package from RStudio, the {gtsummary} package summarizes data sets, regression models, and more, using sensible defaults with highly customizable capabilities. It also allows you to pull values straight from these tables for use in inline text so that every portion of your R markdown analysis report is reproducible. This talk will go over the functionality of the {gtsummary} package, and how you can use it to create beautifully formatted, ready-to-share summary and result tables in a single line of R code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Margie Hannum is a Biostatistician at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center in the Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics. Her research collaborations largely involve using multi-modal genomic and single cell data to characterize cancer subpopulations. She contributes to the {gtsummary} package and uses it every day in her analysis pipelines. Twitter: @Margaret_Hannum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/268481404/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Code-llaboration Hangout</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll kick off the year with a hands-on working session where we&amp;rsquo;ll work together on our own projects or tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come in curious about a subject or looking to make progress on a project you&amp;rsquo;re working on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll divide ourselves into groups who&amp;rsquo;ll be working on similar topics, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have prompts and tutorials at hand for those who don&amp;rsquo;t have a particular project in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that by collaborating with other R-Ladies who share your curiosity you’ll get much further than you would at home with google, and that even if you don’t have a set goal you’ll learn through sharing and receiving tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All experience levels welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll have five groups, for those working on projects related to:
1. Making your website with R and blogdown
2. Building a package
3. Tidy Tuesday
4. Forecasting with time series data
5. Everything else!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to AT&amp;amp;T for hosting us and the R Conference and Lander Analytics for sponsoring pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/267543818/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration with Jenny Bryan</title>
      <link>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To close out 2019, we are thrilled to welcome Jenny Bryan for our R-Ladies New York end-of-year celebration and social! In the potluck tradition of year-end socials past, you are welcome to bring a dessert. Thank you to WarnerMedia for hosting us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:55 pm Introductions and socializing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7 R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10 Welcome from WarnerMedia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-7:45 Jenny Bryan on debugging and troubleshooting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:45-8:30 Socializing and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenny Bryan is a Software Engineer and Data Scientist at RStudio and an Adjunct Professor of Statistics at the University of British Columbia with a Ph.D. in Biostatistics from the University of California, Berkeley. She works on a team that develops open source R packages to make data science faster, easier and more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/266608462/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in healthcare - Ensuring data quality and conducting survival analyses</title>
      <link>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Meetup features a triple-hitter of talks on R in medicine, biostats and health tech. Each speaker will talk for roughly 20 minutes about the topics below, before and after a half hour of socializing and snacks at Flatiron Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, November 14, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Jacqueline Gutman, Jessica Streeter, Sam Adhikari&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Flatiron Health, 233 Spring St&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Rika Gorn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/266165183/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to discuss &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41104077-invisible-women&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invisible Women: Data Bias in a World Designed for Men&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Caroline Criado-Pérez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, November 9, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/265160892/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Make Psychological Scales and Data Dictionaries</title>
      <link>/post/scales-dictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scales-dictionaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speakers for the night will be Emily H Ho from Fordham and Samuel Crane from Amplify. Emily will be talking about working with psychological scales in R. Samuel will be talking about building a data dictionary using blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 22, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Emily H Ho and Samuel Crane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Amplify, 55 Washington St&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Ludmila Janda, Erin Grand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/265361785/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
