<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel Discussion Working with and Learning from COVID-19 data</title>
      <link>/post/panel-working-with-covid-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/panel-working-with-covid-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to host a series of experts to discuss their experiences working with different types of COVID-19 data, insights they&amp;rsquo;ve gleaned, and challenges they&amp;rsquo;ve encountered with these complex and rapidly evolving data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom; the link will be available on this page the morning of the event, and the passcode will be emailed to you.
R-Ladies is dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Please take a moment to review the R-Ladies Global code of conduct (particularly if this is your first time attending!): &lt;a href=&#34;https://rladies.org/code-of-conduct&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://rladies.org/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions regarding accessibility, please email us at nyc@rladies.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bio &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presenters:
Lucy D’Agostino McGowan is an assistant professor in the Mathematics and Statistics Department at Wake Forest University. She received her PhD in Biostatistics from Vanderbilt University and completed her postdoctoral training at Johns Hopkins University Bloomberg School of Public Health. Her research focuses on statistical communication, causal inference, data science pedagogy, and human-data interaction. Dr. D’Agostino McGowan is the 2021 chair of the American Statistical Association’s Committee on Women in Statistics and can be found online at lucymcgowan.com, blogging at livefreeordichotomize.com, on Twitter @LucyStats, and podcasting on the American Journal of Epidemiology partner podcast, Casual Inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynsie Daley is currently serving as a data and analytics supervisor at Intermountain Healthcare based in Salt Lake City. She leads a team of talented data professionals who work across the clinical spectrum supporting areas such as lab, clinical engineering, imaging, and pain. Lynsie also currently serves as Chair of the Women in Analytics group as part of HDAA (Healthcare Data and Analytics Association) and is very passionate about promoting STEM careers to young girls and women and advocating for women currently in the analytics field. She holds both a BS and an MS in statistics from Utah State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kat Hoffman is a biostatistician for the Pulmonary and Critical Care team at Weill Cornell Medicine in New York City. During NYC’s spring 2020 COVID-19 surge she assisted with hospital operations work, and in the time since has transitioned primarily to COVID-19 ICU patient outcome research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Kane is an Assistant Professor of Biostatistics at Yale University and Founder of Telperian Inc., which provides strategic decision support for clinical trial programs. His research focuses on methods and tools for understanding population-level human mobility along with incorporating patient heterogeneity into clinical trial design and analysis. Dr. Kane is a member of Stanford University’s and the R Consortium’s COVID 19 Data Forum and he is a current recipient of the NSF’s Human Networks and Data Science Infrastructure grant which seeks to create a “science of human mobility” in conjunction with AT&amp;amp;T Labs Research. Since the pandemic started he has been trying to quantify the effect of human mobility on the spread of COVID 19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/281092447/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies NYC Lightning Talks (Prep and Submission Workshop)</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks-2021-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks-2021-prep/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to host an online version of one our most popular events this fall - R-Ladies NYC Lightning Talks! We are extending the submission deadline, and are holding this workshop to provide guidance and support for interested speakers. If you are interested in proposing a talk but want to brainstorm ideas, get feedback, or some encouragement, join us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lighting talks are five minute talks. You can talk about anything R, Tech, and/or Data Science related. Looking for ideas? How about talking about a cool package you found, how you use R in your company, a favorite learning resource, your journey into Data Science, or a side project you&amp;rsquo;ve been working on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would especially love to hear from people who&amp;rsquo;ve never presented at a meetup or conference before and/or those who still don&amp;rsquo;t feel confident speaking publicly. A lightning talk can be a great way to start out speaking, as it&amp;rsquo;s quick, low-prep, and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the diversity in the R Community, we&amp;rsquo;re prioritizing presenters who identify as a minority gender (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revised Important Dates
Submissions due: Friday &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;
Notification of acceptance: Sunday &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;
Accepted speakers confirm participation: Wednesday &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;
Slides due to us: Sunday &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;17&lt;/sub&gt;
Lightning Talk Event: &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/280652989/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing your R or Data Science book with Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC</title>
      <link>/post/publishing-your-r-data-science-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/publishing-your-r-data-science-book/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with the R-Ladies DC and Chicago chapters, we are thrilled to co-host this lunchtime presentation with editors from Chapman &amp;amp; Hall/CRC Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom; the link will be available on this page the morning of the event, and the passcode will be emailed to you.
R-Ladies is dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Please take a moment to review the R-Ladies Global code of conduct (particularly if this is your first time attending!): &lt;a href=&#34;https://rladies.org/code-of-conduct&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://rladies.org/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions regarding accessibility, please email us at nyc@rladies.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: In this very practical and interactive workshop, four book editors from Chapman and Hall/CRC will discuss why you should consider publishing an R or Data Science book and why you should work with CRC. The editors will go over the publishing process and provide best practices for shaping your ideas and submitting a book proposal; discuss their bestsellers and popular series as well as emerging topics and trends. The lively discussion will provide plenty of opportunities for the attendees to ask questions and discuss ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bio &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presenters:
Randi Cohen is the Publisher for Computer Science and IT. She commissions across computer science, with a focus on the areas of Data Science, AI and Machine Learning, Computational Science, and Programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Grubbs is a Senior Editor in Statistics. He commissions books in all areas of statistics and data science including but not limited to statistical and machine learning, statistical software, computational and applied statistics, books in R and Python, environmental statistics, data analytics and Bayesian statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lara Spieker is an Editor for Statistics. She commissions books in all areas of data science and statistics, such as computational and applied statistics, statistical software, books on R and Python, and Bayesian Statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Calver is a Senior Publisher for Statistics, Mathematics and Physics. He commissions books in statistics and data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/280385222/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Plots to Explore Data Using R</title>
      <link>/post/making-plots-to-explore-data-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-plots-to-explore-data-using-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our August event, we are excited to host Professor Di Cook of Monash University who will be presenting strategies for making plots to explore data using R. There is an interactive component to her talk, and she has requested that attendees download packages tidyverse, plotly, forcats, and nullabor from CRAN, as well as yowie from Github using remotes::install_github(&amp;ldquo;numbats/yowie&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:50: &amp;ldquo;Making plots to explore data using R&amp;rdquo;
7:50-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: A recent article by Hullman and Gelman appeared in the Harvard Data Science Review (&lt;a href=&#34;https://hdsr.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/w075glo6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://hdsr.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/w075glo6&lt;/a&gt;) arguing the need for more theoretical work to support interactive exploratory graphics. It is accompanied by six short informative commentaries. Plots have always been an instrument for data exploration, and yet it is a difficult task, to teach and to conduct. Here we will give a walk-through on organizing your work to make plots to explore data and to quantitatively check if what you see is spurious or special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bio &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Dianne Cook is Professor of Business Analytics at Monash University in Melbourne, Australia. Her research is in the area of data visualization, especially the visualization of high-dimensional data using tours with low-dimensional projections, and projection pursuit. A current focus is on bridging the gap between exploratory graphics and statistical inference. Di utilizes technology such as virtual environments, Amazon’s Mechanical Turk, and eye-tracking in her work, and makes an effort to share her work with open-source software. Di is a Fellow of the American Statistical Association, elected member of the International Statistical Institute, past-editor of the Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics, elected Member of the R Foundation, and current editor of the R Journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/280162747/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Book Club - Algorithms of Oppression</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-book-club-algorithms-of-oppression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-book-club-algorithms-of-oppression/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our August book club, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing &amp;ldquo;Algorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce Racism&amp;rdquo; by Safiya Umoja Noble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Update&lt;/strong&gt;: While this month&amp;rsquo;s Book Club was originally scheduled to be in person, in light of oppressive heat this week in NYC and expected thunderstorms throughout the afternoon of Saturday, August 14th, this will now be an online event. The zoom link will be available on this page Saturday morning, and a message with the meeting passcode will go out at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/279410109/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating model en mass with workflowsets</title>
      <link>/post/creating-model-en-mass-with-workflowsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-model-en-mass-with-workflowsets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our second July event, we are excited to host Max Kuhn of RStudio who will be presenting on the workflowsets package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:50: &amp;ldquo;Creating model en mass with workflowsets&amp;rdquo;
7:50-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: The tidymodels packages allow users to create and optimize models and their pre-processing steps (e.g. PCA, feature encodings, etc). With new data, it is common to try a variety of models to determine what works best. The workflowsets package enables users to easily evaluate, rank, and even combine (with the stacks package) myriad combinations of models and pre-processors. the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bio &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Max Kuhn is a software engineer at RStudio. He is currently working on improving R&amp;rsquo;s modeling capabilities. He was a Senior Director of Nonclinical Statistics at Pfizer Global R&amp;amp;D in Connecticut. He was applying models in the pharmaceutical and diagnostic industries for over 18 years. Max has a Ph.D. in Biostatistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max is the author of R packages for techniques in machine learning and reproducible research. He, and Kjell Johnson, wrote the book Applied Predictive Modeling, which won the Ziegel award from the American Statistical Association, which recognizes the best book reviewed in Technometrics in 2015. Their latest book, Feature Engineering and Selection, was published in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/279465886/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Epidemiologist R Handbook</title>
      <link>/post/the-epidemiologist-r-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-epidemiologist-r-handbook/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our July event, we are excited to host authors Neale Batra, Aminata Ndiaye, and Paula Blomquist, who will present the Epidemiologist R Handbook, a free new code reference book targeted to R users working in applied epidemiology and public health, but handy for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:50: &amp;ldquo;The Epidemiologist R Handbook - a new resource for public health practitioners (and everyone else)&amp;rdquo;
7:50-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Amidst the COVID-19 pandemic, 50 epidemiologists from across the world joined forces seeking to improve access to R and elevate the quality of analytics in public health. Writing in their spare time, they produced The Epidemiologist R Handbook (epiRhandbook.com), a free new code reference book targeted to R users working in applied epidemiology and public health, but handy for anyone. The &amp;ldquo;Epi R Handbook&amp;rdquo; is full of code snippets and tutorials addressing day-to-day data cleaning, analysis, visualization, reporting, and collaboration challenges. The handbook also comes in an offline version for use in settings with low internet connectivity. Since its launch, the handbook has been used 200,000 times by 36,000 people in 203 countries/territories. In this session, founder Neale Batra is joined by co-authors Paula Blomquist and Aminata Ndiaye to discuss the handbook&amp;rsquo;s utility for you, the intersection of R and public health, the project&amp;rsquo;s next steps, and the editorial and technical challenges they faced creating this resource for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bios &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neale Batra is the founder and editor of the Epidemiologist R Handbook project. As an applied epidemiologist, he tries to leverage R to better inform decision-making in health emergencies. Currently he works for the COVID-19 analytics team at the World Health Organization (Geneva), but has previously worked internationally for Doctors without Borders and in the US for the public health departments of Philadelphia and Santa Clara County. He loves teaching, and in his spare time enjoys guiding rock climbing and backpacking trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paula Blomquist is an epidemiologist in Public Health England, where she works on the national surveillance of COVID-19. She spends much of her day job creating data visualisations and R markdown reports to monitor variants, with a particular fondness of {patchwork} and {flextable}. Paula has also used R for analyses in international deployments, most recently with the UK Emergency Medical Team to Samoa during the 2019 measles epidemic. Paula is a contributor to the Epidemiologist R Handbook, and excited to encourage more people in public health to learn to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aminata NDIAYE is a Biostatistician at Epicentre Research Department-MSF (Doctors without Borders). She graduated from Paris Descartes University School of Medicine in Public health and from Paris Saclay University School of Sciences in Bioinformatics and Biostatistics. She previously worked at World Health Organization (WHO) as an analyst during the 10th Ebola virus disease (EVD) outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and at Karolinska Institute’s department of medical epidemiology and biostatistics as a Research assistant. She is co-organizer and member of the R-ladies Stockholm group since its creation, in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/278990032/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization - Color Palettes, Themes, and Schemes</title>
      <link>/post/data-visualization-color-palettes-themes-and-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-visualization-color-palettes-themes-and-schemes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our June event, R-Ladies Anna Sofia Kircher and Joyce Robbins will share short talks about using color palettes, themes, and schemes to improve data visualization in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:30: “ggplot and I” by Anna Sofia Kircher
7:30-7:55: “Does your color palette match your data?” by Joyce Robbins
7:55-8:15: Questions and wrap-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ggplot and I”
Speaker: Anna Sofia Kircher&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: This talk will be about how to use ggplot themes and how to personalize them for your purposes. This is motivated by my own obsession with colors and my own experience that different plots with different audiences respond differently to different themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Anna Sofia Kircher is the data scientist at Lendable and works with data of various fintechs in emerging and frontier markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Does your color palette match your data?”
Speaker: Joyce Robbins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: One of the most common graphical mistakes is choosing an inappropriate color scheme for your data. In this talk, I’ll explain how sequential, diverging and qualitative color schemes are each suited to a different type of data. We’ll then look at a variety of plots that could be improved with alternative color choices. My hope is that these examples will serve as conversation starters for a lively discussion on matching color to data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Joyce Robbins (@jtrnyc) is a Lecturer in the Department of Statistics at Columbia University. She specializes in data visualization and statistical literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/278643264/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Wrangling to Writing - Analyzing Data and Creating Production-Level Code</title>
      <link>/post/from-wrangling-to-writing-analyzing-data-and-creating-production-level-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/from-wrangling-to-writing-analyzing-data-and-creating-production-level-code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our April event, we will have two guest speakers. Megan Robertson will be talking about how to write production level data science code, while Natalie O&amp;rsquo;Shea will be discussing how to use the nyccensus package and how to wrangle/use census data for equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
6:05 - 6:10 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
6:10 - 6:40 : Natalie&amp;rsquo;s talk on NYC Census data with time for Q&amp;amp;A
6:40-7pm: Megan&amp;rsquo;s talk on creating production level data science code with time for Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introducing nyccensus: Leveraging Census Data for Equity in NYC&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Natalie O&amp;rsquo;Shea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: This talk will introduce the nyccensus package and associated Shiny dashboard and share examples of how census data can be leveraged to help address equity issues. The nyccensus package is a simple data-sharing package meant to ease the pains of accessing and wrangling publicly-available response rate data from the 2020 Decennial Census as well as other relevant demographic data from the American Community Survey at various geographic levels in New York City. I will share some lessons learned and examples of how these data can be used to better understand and address equity issues in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Natalie O&amp;rsquo;Shea is a researcher and data visualization specialist with a passion for equity, accessibility, and human-centered design. She started her data science journey during graduate school, falling in love with all things R in her coursework and research. She was part of CUNY&amp;rsquo;s first Data for Public Good cohort before taking a position as a Community Outreach Data Analyst with the NYC Census 2020 initiative and then working as a Data Visualization Specialist at NYC Test &amp;amp; Trace Corps. She is currently working as a Data Visualization Analyst on the Research and Learning Engineering team at Edmentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Creating Production Level Data Science Code&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Megan Robertson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Writing code is a big part of working as a data scientist. You write code throughout all stages of a project from exploratory data analysis to building models. This talk focuses on creating production code from a proof of concept analysis or model. How do you organize and adapt all the code created to get to a proof of concept? Do you feel overwhelmed by everything you need to do? At the end of this talk you’ll walk away with tips and strategies to make your own production code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Megan Robertson is a Senior Data Scientist at Nike. She has multiple years of experience applying data science in retail settings. She first became interested in math and statistics through sports analytics, and wrote her Master’s thesis in collaboration with an NBA team. Her background includes training in Bayesian methodology, statistical modeling, machine learning and more. Megan has delivered multiple talks on various aspects of data science from building a career and project management to writing code. She is currently writing her first data science book, Mastering Communication in Data Science, in partnership with Manning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/277533609/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus on Content - Create Enterprise-Worthy Shiny Applications with Periscope</title>
      <link>/post/focus-on-content-create-enterprise-worthy-shiny-applications-with-periscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/focus-on-content-create-enterprise-worthy-shiny-applications-with-periscope/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our March event, Dr. Connie Brett, the CEO, founder, &amp;amp; principal data scientist of Aggregate Genius, Inc. will talk to us about the Periscope package and enterprise-level Shiny apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda (times approximate):
6:05 - 6:10 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
6:10 + : Connie&amp;rsquo;s talk on periscope with time for Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talk Abstract &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Focus on Content: Create Enterprise-Worthy Shiny Applications with Periscope&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Dr. Connie Brett&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: The periscope R package is a framework that you can use to significantly speed up your shiny development – whether you are just writing your first collaborative application or taking on a bigger project that will be deployed to many users. Periscope can significantly &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; your Shiny game by jump-starting development in a way that is flexible and robust. This lets you focus on the content of your application, as opposed to the mechanics (and those insidious pitfalls!) of building a shiny application for multiple users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bio: Dr. Connie Brett is the CEO, Founder, and Principal Data Scientist of Aggregate Genius Inc. located in BC, Canada. She is experienced in using many types of models and algorithms as well as architecting cutting-edge big-data analytics-integrated platforms. She has submitted publications and patents; contributes to and maintains R packages and frameworks (such as periscope) in the open-source community; and attends and speaks at industry events. With over 20 years spent focusing on producing solid analytical models, software and visualization tools – as well as custom IT solutions architecture – she continues to carry forward her passion for helping clients realize true business insights from analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/276969681/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Code-laboration</title>
      <link>/post/tidy-tuesday-code-laboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidy-tuesday-code-laboration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a collaborative exploration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tidy Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; dataset of the week! First, we will have a short demo of working through a previous Tidy Tuesday dataset, led by Ludmila Janda. Then we will work in groups to do some exploration and visualization of the dataset of the week and then we will come together to share our work. No preparation is necessary but participants are welcome to check out the dataset(s) and come with any ideas they may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page the morning of the event. We will request your email address upon registration to ensure you receive the Zoom passcode on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/276630718/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Book Club</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-book-club-data-feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-book-club-data-feminism/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details
For our February book club, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing &amp;ldquo;Data Feminism&amp;rdquo; by Catherine D&amp;rsquo;Ignazio and Lauren F. Klein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page the morning of the event. We will request your email address upon registration to ensure you receive the Zoom passcode on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/276116912/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join our team! R-Ladies NYC Board Information Session</title>
      <link>/post/join-our-team-r-ladies-nyc-board-information-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/join-our-team-r-ladies-nyc-board-information-session/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If getting more involved with your local R-Ladies New York chapter was on your list of 2021 resolutions, here’s your chance! We are looking for new members to join us as event organizers on the R-Ladies NYC Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information session will be a meet and greet with current board members: we’ll introduce ourselves, explain responsibilities and the expected time commitment of a board member, and highlight initiatives we’d like to pursue in 2021. We will also provide next steps for how to get involved. We are happy to take questions and suggestions for future meetups from our community, so please feel free to attend with feedback even if you may not be interested in joining the board as an organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining the board but are unable to attend this meeting, please connect with us via Slack or email us at nyc@rladies.org with your questions, thoughts, and comments. We’ll be happy to follow up with more information!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event. We will request your email address upon registration to ensure you receive the Zoom passcode on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/275871697/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration for Women and Gender Minorities</title>
      <link>/post/end-of-year-celebration-for-women-and-gender-minorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/end-of-year-celebration-for-women-and-gender-minorities/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Please note: At the request of members of our community for an R-Ladies space exclusively for minority genders, this event is limited to those who identify as such (including but not limited to women, trans men, non-binary, and gender nonconforming individuals). Male allies have been great supporters of our chapter and the R-Ladies mission to promote gender diversity in the R Community &amp;ndash; for which we are grateful! &amp;ndash; and we believe the best way male allies can support us this month is by honoring the need for and benefit of such a space.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays! To close out 2020, we are thrilled to host a virtual version of our annual end-of-year celebration and social! We&amp;rsquo;ll utilize breakout rooms to allow participants to connect (or re-connect) with other members of our community in smaller groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/em&gt; To RSVP for this event, you must complete and submit this Google form: &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/v3eEg4nXSzH9s5D4A&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://forms.gle/v3eEg4nXSzH9s5D4A&lt;/a&gt; While you may RSVP via Meetup to let others know you plan to attend, Zoom link information will only be shared via email with those who register through the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10: Welcome and R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-8:30: Breakout room chats (3-5 people, and we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some topics to inspire conversation!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/274929711/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with the Authors of &#34;Data Science in Education Using R&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/q-and-a-with-the-authors-of-data-science-in-education-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/q-and-a-with-the-authors-of-data-science-in-education-using-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event. We will request your email address upon registration to ensure you receive the newly required Zoom passcode on the day of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda-subject-to-change&#34;&gt;Agenda (subject to change):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30-7:35 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:35-8:05: Book talk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:05 - end Audience Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-description&#34;&gt;Book Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Science in Education Using R is the go-to reference for learning data science in the education field. The book answers questions like: What does a data scientist in education do? How do I get started learning R, the popular open-source statistical programming language? And what does a data analysis project in education look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re just getting started with R in an education job, this is the book you’ll want with you. This book gets you started with R by teaching the building blocks of programming that you’ll use many times in your career. The book takes a &amp;ldquo;learn by doing&amp;rdquo; approach and offers eight analysis walkthroughs that show you a data analysis from start to finish, complete with code for you to practice with. The book finishes with how to get involved in the data science community and how to integrate data science in your education job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-bios&#34;&gt;Speaker Bios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan A. Estrellado (@RyanEs) has served public schools for over seventeen years as a school psychologist and administrator. Ryan writes about working with data, education, and other projects at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ryanestrellado.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ryanestrellado.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily A. Freer (@ebovee09) is the Director of Educational Development and Assessment at the Marquette University School of Dentistry. Learn more about Emily at &lt;a href=&#34;https://emilyfreer.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://emilyfreer.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesse Mostipak (@kierisi) is the Community Advocate for Kaggle, and has worked both as a high school science teacher and lead data scientist within education non-profits. To follow Jesse’s learning adventures in Python and deep learning, head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jessemaegan.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://jessemaegan.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isabella C. Velásquez (@ivelasq3) is a data analyst committed to nonprofit work with the goal of reducing racial and socioeconomic inequities. To follow Isabella’s personal projects, join her at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ivelasq.rbind.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ivelasq.rbind.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/274197702/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
