<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Code-llaboration Hangout</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll kick off the year with a hands-on working session where we&amp;rsquo;ll work together on our own projects or tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come in curious about a subject or looking to make progress on a project you&amp;rsquo;re working on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll divide ourselves into groups who&amp;rsquo;ll be working on similar topics, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have prompts and tutorials at hand for those who don&amp;rsquo;t have a particular project in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that by collaborating with other R-Ladies who share your curiosity you’ll get much further than you would at home with google, and that even if you don’t have a set goal you’ll learn through sharing and receiving tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All experience levels welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll have five groups, for those working on projects related to:
1. Making your website with R and blogdown
2. Building a package
3. Tidy Tuesday
4. Forecasting with time series data
5. Everything else!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to AT&amp;amp;T for hosting us and the R Conference and Lander Analytics for sponsoring pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/267543818/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration with Jenny Bryan</title>
      <link>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To close out 2019, we are thrilled to welcome Jenny Bryan for our R-Ladies New York end-of-year celebration and social! In the potluck tradition of year-end socials past, you are welcome to bring a dessert. Thank you to WarnerMedia for hosting us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:55 pm Introductions and socializing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7 R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10 Welcome from WarnerMedia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-7:45 Jenny Bryan on debugging and troubleshooting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:45-8:30 Socializing and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenny Bryan is a Software Engineer and Data Scientist at RStudio and an Adjunct Professor of Statistics at the University of British Columbia with a Ph.D. in Biostatistics from the University of California, Berkeley. She works on a team that develops open source R packages to make data science faster, easier and more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/266608462/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in healthcare - Ensuring data quality and conducting survival analyses</title>
      <link>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Meetup features a triple-hitter of talks on R in medicine, biostats and health tech. Each speaker will talk for roughly 20 minutes about the topics below, before and after a half hour of socializing and snacks at Flatiron Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, November 14, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Jacqueline Gutman, Jessica Streeter, Sam Adhikari&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Flatiron Health, 233 Spring St&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Rika Gorn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/266165183/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to discuss &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41104077-invisible-women&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invisible Women: Data Bias in a World Designed for Men&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Caroline Criado-Pérez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, November 9, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/265160892/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Make Psychological Scales and Data Dictionaries</title>
      <link>/post/scales-dictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scales-dictionaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speakers for the night will be Emily H Ho from Fordham and Samuel Crane from Amplify. Emily will be talking about working with psychological scales in R. Samuel will be talking about building a data dictionary using blogdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 22, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Emily H Ho and Samuel Crane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Amplify, 55 Washington St&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Ludmila Janda, Erin Grand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/265361785/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Superlearner with sl3 and Parameterizing R Markdown Reports</title>
      <link>/post/superlearner-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/superlearner-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speakers for the night will be Elizabeth Mauer and Kat Hoffman from Weill Cornell Medicine. Elizabeth will be talking about parameterized reporting in R Markdown. Kat will be discussing the Superlearner machine learning algorithm using the sl3 package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, September 10, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Elizabeth Mauer and Kat Hoffman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Weill Cornell Medicine, 1300 York Ave&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Elizabeth Sweeney, Alejandra Gerosa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/264137849/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Career in Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/build-a-career-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/build-a-career-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies NYC is proud and excited that one of our members, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hookedondata.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emily Robinson&lt;/a&gt;, is co-authoring a book with a fellow R-lady, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jnolis.com/writing.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jacqueline Nolis&lt;/a&gt;! The book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bestbook.cool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Build a Career in Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is available for pre-order, which comes with online access to all currently available chapters (1-9) access to the rest of the chapters as they come out. This book is a practical guide to preparing for, finding, and excelling in a data science role. It&amp;rsquo;s written by two influential people in the R and data science communities and includes interviews from other data scientists, such as Brooke Watson, one of the R-Ladies NYC board members.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to WoRk(flows)</title>
      <link>/post/back-to-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/back-to-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our speakers David Shilane and Madison Volpe will share tools and workflows to increase productivity and integrate R with Tableau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Monday, August 26, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: David Shilane and Madison Volpe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Gabriela Hempfling, Alejandra Gerosa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/263601076/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to discuss &lt;a href=&#34;https://kieranhealy.org/publications/dataviz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Kieran Healy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, August 31, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/263376046/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hex Sticker Result</title>
      <link>/post/hex-sticker-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hex-sticker-result/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R-Ladies NYC call for a hex sticker design produced three creative and unique submissions. We would like to thank Ayanthi Gunawardana, Kat Hoffman, and Ludmila Janda for their involvement with the R-Ladies NYC community and time spent crafting their designs! Below, each of these R-Ladies shares her inspiration behind her design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/ayanthi.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HoneyBadger88&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ayanthi Gunawardana&lt;/a&gt;: My goal was the keep the logo and colors as simple as possible to ensure it could be scaled to any size. I saw the negative space in the bottom of the &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; and immediately knew I wanted to use it creatively for the logo. I picked NYC landmarks that would fit in that space and ordered them in decreasing height to make sure it still looked like the letter &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/kat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rkatlady&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kat Hoffman&lt;/a&gt;: I moved to New York last August and immediately realized one of my favorite activities—besides attending R-Ladies events, of course!—was walking around the city to look at all the amazing street art. I tried to emulate this urban uniqueness in my design while emphasizing inclusivity (rainbow color scheme) and iconic NYC (Statue of Liberty crown over “Ladies”). I really enjoyed learning Adobe Illustrator to make my submission, and I am looking forward to representing R-Ladies in ggplot form on my laptop soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/luda.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ludmila_janda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ludmila Janda&lt;/a&gt;: I was inspired by our city and wanted to find a way use data and R for the sticker so I got the heights of several iconic structures and their spires and made a graph with ggplot. Then I used google drawings to make buildings and laid them over the graph to make the final image, which I used with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuangchuangYu/hexSticker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hexSticker package&lt;/a&gt; for the final product. Many thanks to Guangchuang Yu for quickly closing my issue (#62) for his package in order to let the URL angle vary as parameter - I used that for the &amp;ldquo;NYC&amp;rdquo; part of the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Ludmila Janda! Her design was chosen as the winner in a tight Twitter poll on June 20th. Please join us at future R-Ladies NYC events for your opportunity to snag a new hex sticker and represent our chapter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/poll.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come hang out with R-Ladies at the Royale Bar outdoor patio for an afternoon social full of fun, board games, and splendid R conversation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinks and food will be available for purchase. Collaborative, multi-player and two-player table games will be provided, but feel free to bring your own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, July 13, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm - 5:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Royale, 157 Loisaida Ave, New York, NY, 10009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/262478374/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and Fantasy Baseball?</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you so much to Anisha BharathSingh, who originally wrote this post for her blog, found &lt;a href=&#34;https://journeytodatascientist.blog/2019/05/24/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We are reposting her post with her consent. If you are an R-Lady interested in writing a blog post or cross-posting a blog post on your own blog, please let us know (via email nyc@rladies.org or via DM on twitter @RLadiesNYC)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, May 23, I attended my first R-Ladies NYC meetup! R-Ladies NYC is an organization that promotes gender diversity amongst the R community by organizing a series of events (including this meetup) to support women who want to learn R or want to share their experiences as R programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drafting-a-fantasy-baseball-team-with-r&#34;&gt;Drafting a Fantasy Baseball Team with R&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meetup included an interesting take on data science – using R to draft a fantasy baseball team! This was presented by Angeline Protacio, a self-employed data scientist at Protacio Analytics LLC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, Angeline spends her time playing fantasy baseball. For those not familiar with fantasy baseball, as Angeline explained, you create your own fantasy baseball team with real players from any existing team. Each day, you decide what your lineup will be, and how well your team does depends on each players actual performance that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angeline wanted to use her data science skills to draft a competitive fantasy baseball team. To do so, Angeline used a series of &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.mlb.com/glossary/standard-stats&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;player scoring categories&lt;/a&gt; including: R, HR, RBI, SO, SB, OPS, WAR. She first took a look at how a player’s position affected their scoring categories with ggplot visualizations. From this, she found that outfielders had better offensive stats and suggests to draft your outfielders first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Metric Comparing Overall Performance for Players&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, in order to determine which specific players to draft, Angeline tried looking for a summary statistic of all scoring categories to compare all players to each other, but could not find any. While there is the WAR (Wins Above Replacement) scoring category that summarizes a players contribution to their team, this only does so with respect to being substituted by a replacement player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led her to creating her own metric. With the help of the tidyverse package she: 1) filtered for players who had an average plate appearance above 300; 2) selected player id, position, Name, Team and all scoring categories; and 3) mutated her data frame with the players information to include a z-score for each scoring category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This z-score is used to determine how much better a player performed than the mean for that category. Summing these z-scores provided an overall performance metric for each player in comparison to all other players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top MLB Players of 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using her new metric, Angeline arranged her new data frame in a descending order to find the Top 5 MLB players for 2018:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Trout (Angels) – total z-score: 11.889&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giancarlo Stanton (Yankees) – total z-score: 11.869&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nolan Arenado (Rockies) – total z-score: 8.766&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryce Harper (Phillies) – total z-score: 8.646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthony Rizzo (Cubs) – total z-score: 8.343&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angelinepro/rladiesnyc_may2019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; for the repository with all of Angeline’s code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this only accounts for one part of drafting a fantasy baseball team, this just goes to show that you can use data science for pretty much anything!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are hosting a very special event - lightning talks from the R-Ladies community! Come out to hear a variety of R &amp;amp; Data Science talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Wednesday, June 19, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:00pm - 9:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: A whole lot of R ladies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: OppenheimerFunds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Elizbeth Sweeny&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/262079485/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYR 2019 Speaker Experience and Tips</title>
      <link>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-05-28-nyr-conference-tips/stickers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New York R conference attracts a diverse yet technical audience which means the bar is high for all invited speakers. This year, over half the speakers were women, including several R-Ladies NYC members. It was such a fun and good experience that we decided to collaborate and write a blog post to encourage others to speak at conferences and provide some tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Ludmila Janda, Emily Robinson, Emily Dodwell, Gabriela Hempfling, Elizabeth Sweeny, Soumya Kalra, Brooke Watson, Amanda Dobbyn, Letisha Smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips-on-speaking&#34;&gt;Tips on Speaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Summarize your talk to someone you know well but isn’t too familiar with the subject matter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice a couple times. If your team at work is willing, schedule time to give your talk several days or a week before the conference. Ludmila’s team listened to her talk twice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take deep breaths before you get on stage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anyone raises their hand and then starts talking in the middle of your talk just say “I’m sorry we aren’t taking any questions” and keep it moving! Don’t let them get you out of your flow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people look like they’re frowning when they’re trying to listen. Don’t be distracted by reading too much into their expressions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have fun on stage and don’t get embarrassed during your walk out song&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the speakers&amp;rsquo; lounge to prepare and decompress&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks can be a great way to practice! They are five minute talks in front of a smaller audience that can help you get the format down and trial run an idea. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeJom9L9SBqYPr0gU_GVwPXPvYqv167tLafrv2SaBJYvXJK7Q/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;You can submit a talk for the upcoming R-Ladies NYC lightning talks event here!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rladiesnyc.org/post/lightning-talks-roundup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s lightning talks can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hookedondata.org/giving-your-first-data-science-talk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More tips from Emily Robinson on her blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to R-ladies for support and feedback before giving a talk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, one of the hardest things about giving a talk is getting yourself to start preparing your slides. Sometimes, it can feel hard to even choose what to use to make the slides. Therefore, we are including a section on what we used to make our slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerpoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As timeless as Michael Scott, there’s no shame in “Powerpoint, Powerpoint, Powerpoint”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be helpful even if you want to just storyboard the idea first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Gabriela, Emily R, Elizabeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keynote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerpoint for Millenials™&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rumored to be used by Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Brooke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xaringan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cool newish package in R!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits: you can easily make your slides in R and immediately see updates to the slides, easily incorporate talk notes, includes a presentation mode with a timer, formats slides very easily and nicely, allows you to experiment with interesting themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawbacks: Has a bit of learning curve, can be a bit buggy (sometimes having the immediate viewing of changes on can really slow down ability to edit the slides), it was a bit hard to deal with unmirroring the display and dragging one set of slides to the big screen, not as easy as using presenter mode in something like powerpoint, but if you don’t need notes there is no need to worry about this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Ludmila, Amanda, and Soumya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits: Google slides makes it very easy to create beautiful slides with the Explore feature. If you type text or paste an image on the slide, Google will automatically recommend 10 ways to better format the slide. Plus, using the Google Slides app makes it very easy to practice your presentation during your commute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawback: While Google supports version control with the Version History feature, it does not allow reproducible research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Letisha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;walk-out-music&#34;&gt;Walk out Music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NYR has a fun tradition of letting the speaker pick a song to walk out to, but this can feel like a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; decision. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the song only plays for about 10 - 20 seconds and it might not start right where you would want it to, even if you give a specific time to start the song. These were our walk out songs this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludmila Janda (Building the Tidyverse From Scratch: Teaching Data Cleaning and Visualization with R-inspired Custom Scratch Blocks): Mi Gente - J Balvin, Willy William, Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Dodwell (From Tangled Lassos to Boosted Trees: Iterative Research in Practice): Run the World (Girls) - Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Robinson (Everything You Wanted to Know About Making R Packages but Were Afraid to Ask): Mrs. Robinson, Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabriela Hempfling (I’ll Have What She’s Having (and Other Models of Consumer Behavior): Bad Bad News - Leon Bridges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Sweeny (Neuroimaging Analysis in R): Insane in the Brain - Cypress Hill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soumya Kalra (Becoming a better finance practitioner): Forget my name - Danko Jones&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brooke Watson (Using R to defend immigrant&amp;rsquo;s rights at the ACLU): Freedom - Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda Dobbyn (This Talk is on Fire: Using Twitter and Google to Track Fires in NYC): We Didn’t Start the Fire, Billy Joel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letisha Smith (Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art): I&amp;rsquo;m Every Woman - Chaka Khan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/0VAHe4mcJDB5iWBgypMq2X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tech Ladies&lt;/a&gt; playlist also has a lot of empowering singles to choose from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-05-28-nyr-conference-tips/rladies.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to discuss &lt;strong&gt;How Not To Be Wrong&lt;/strong&gt; by Jordan Ellenberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, May 25th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/261214466/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
