<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/launching-r-ladies-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/launching-r-ladies-nyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come listen to two women who have come into Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, May 23rd, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:15pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Angeline and Kaelen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: JP Morgan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/r-package-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-package-workshop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bring your laptop and come out to our next workshop to learn about building your very own R package!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/259858458/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s workshop will focus on R package development from the ground up. We will cover package structure, set-up, creating functions, documentation, testing, dependencies, sharing the package with others, package vignettes, hex stickers, and other methods. An example package will be developed during the workshop so attendees can follow along and create their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Zabor and Erin Grand are also going to be serving has TAs for this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, March 26, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: Vroom (1375 Broadway Ave, 11th floor)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sebastian-s-bio&#34;&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian is a data scientist at Vroom, an ecommerce start-up that focuses on selling used cars that are delivered to your door. Previously, Sebastian was doing research on cancer genomics as a postdoc at Yale University. He has also been a strong advocate for R-Ladies and is an experienced CRAN package author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Seborinos/rladiesnyc_package_workshop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Pipelines with Text and Data</title>
      <link>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are excited this month to host two very active R-Ladies from our chapter: Amanda Dobbyn and Maryam Jahanshahi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/258458666/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesday, February 12, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 6:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt; WeWork (205 Hudson S)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda&amp;rsquo;s talk will focus on the package &amp;lsquo;drake&amp;rsquo;. &lt;code&gt;Drake&lt;/code&gt; is a package designed to make designing and executing analysis pipelines easier and more reproducible. In this talk Amanda will run through an example of how &lt;code&gt;drake&lt;/code&gt; can be used to manage an analysis workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryam&amp;rsquo;s talk will focus on designing and executing text processing pipelines. In this talk, Maryam will share lessons and takeaways on text processing and data management for natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amanda-s-bio&#34;&gt;Amanda&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda is a data scientist at Earlybird Software, a cloud application and data consulting company. She was previously an organizer of R-Ladies Chicago before escaping that frozen tundra for this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maryam-s-bio&#34;&gt;Maryam&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryam is a Research Scientist at TapRecruit, a software startup that helps companies improve the fairness and efficiency of their recruiting processes. In a past life, Maryam was a cancer biologist and a data journalist. In a future life, Maryam hopes to be a carpenter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Arrival and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6:30-7:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Talks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30-8pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Networking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Algorithms to live by</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At our next book club meeting, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss Algorithms to Live By, by Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/257130300/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please support our wonderful host bookstore, Rizzoli, by ordering the book directly from them &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/algorithms-live-computer-science-human-decisions-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;through this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt; Saturday, January 26, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt; Rizzoli Bookstore (1133 Broadway Ave)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git with Joyce</title>
      <link>/post/git-with-joyce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-with-joyce/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are kicking off this year with an introduction to Github by Joyce Robbins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/257698665/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hands on workshop so please bring your laptop to follow along and please be prompt to make sure the workshop kicks off on time:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Wednesday, January 9, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: Columbia University (1255 Amsterdam Ave, Room 903)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-joyce&#34;&gt;About Joyce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joyce Robbins, Ph.D., is Lecturer in Discipline in the Statistics Department at Columbia University, where she specializes in data visualization. She is a member of the R Forwards (R Foundation taskforce on women and other under-represented groups) teaching team, and elected to serve as publications officer of the Statistical Graphics Section of the American Statistical Association Section beginning in 2018. Robbins received her doctorate in sociology from Columbia University, her M.A. in sociology and anthropology from Tel Aviv University and her B.S.E. in civil engineering and operations research from Princeton University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Joyce&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found at their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jtr13/codehelp/blob/master/GitHubWorkflow.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 End of Year Social</title>
      <link>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays! For the end of the year we are looking to celebrate how far R-Ladies New York has come and thank all of you for your incredible support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/256736860/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are doing this potluck style so &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ytU6boa7oDAM3gujH0NRIy9ezS03P4Q4BWx6v6StIcY/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to bring something to the party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dress in casual or holiday gear - we welcome it all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Monday, December 10, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center (33 Thomas Street New York, NY)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility and Communication in R</title>
      <link>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This month it is our pleasure to have Noam Ross and our very own Ludmila Janda present on Reproducibility and Communication in R!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/255925263/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, November 6, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:45pm - General networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:45-6:55pm - R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:25pm - Reproducibility in an Office World: A Brief History of Failures and the Odd Success by Noam Ross&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:25-7:55pm A Data Odyssey: Communicating Results With Coworkers
by Ludamila Janda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:00pm R-Ladies Community announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:00-8:30pm Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducibility-in-an-office-world-a-brief-history-of-failures-and-the-odd-success&#34;&gt;Reproducibility in an Office World: A Brief History of Failures and the Odd Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many data scientists operate at the interface of two cultures with different tools and workflows - programmatic workflows (e.g., R Markdown) and WYSIWYG documents (e.g., Microsoft Word). The noisy interface between these can be an impediment to reproducibility, as well as a royal pain. I will discuss approaches I and others have tried in dealing with these issues, and why and how some have failed and succeeded. I&amp;rsquo;ll also demonstrate some tools, including packages officer and rvg and some rarely used feaures of rmarkdown that ease the flow when collaborating across the divide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noam Ross is a Senior Research Scientist at EcoHealth Alliance, a non-profit in NYC that researches the connections between human and wildlife health. Noam builds models to understand and predict disease circulation in wildlife and spillover into people. Noam is also editor for software peer review at rOpenSci, a developer collective that builds R packages and catalyzes communities to enable open research and data. He has a Ph.D. in ecology from the University of California-Davis. Follow him on twitter at @noamross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Noam&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noamross/2018-11-06-rladies-talk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Noam&amp;rsquo;s GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-data-odyssey-communicating-results-with-coworkers&#34;&gt;A Data Odyssey: Communicating Results With Coworkers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, data scientists are tasked with communicating their results with people in the workplace who do not share the same technical background. Bridging the gaps between parties can be a perilous journey. In this talk, I will discuss how I have attempted to navigate this tricky terrain and provide some pointers for clear language use and data visualization choices. I’ll demonstrate how I pass on insights through visualizations using packages such as ggridges and ggalluvial and how I use rmarkdown to craft reports and take my coworkers on data adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludmila Janda is a Data Scientist at Amplify, a pioneer in K–12 education since 2000, leading the way in next-generation curriculum and assessment. Today, Amplify serves four million students in all 50 states. Luda’s work provides insights on student and teacher usage, student success, and Amplify’s broader impact. She is a proud RLady and has a Master’s in Public Policy from the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill. Follow her on twitter at @ludmila_janda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Ludmila&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ljanda/rladiesnyc_talk_11_06_2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ludmila&amp;rsquo;s GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Computing in R</title>
      <link>/post/parallel-computing-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallel-computing-in-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to host Jared Lander, Chief Data Scientist of Lander Analytics, the organizer of the New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup and the New York R Conference, and author of R for Everyone, to talk about parallel computing in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/254762100/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, November 6, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker&lt;/strong&gt;: Jared Lander&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: OppenheimerFunds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-7: Food &amp;amp; networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7-7:10: Kick-off and announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:10-7:45: Talk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:45-8:30: Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk&#34;&gt;Talk:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants their code to run faster and there are numerous ways to achieve this goal. We start by looking at popular packages &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;data.table&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;purrr&lt;/code&gt; and the corresponding parallel implementations. We then turn our attention to writing simple C++ functions integrated into R, both sequentially and in parallel. We also build a &lt;code&gt;data.frame&lt;/code&gt; aggregation function, starting sequentially, ending in parallel. Throughout this talk we see how to speed up code by running in parallel, locally and across nodes, in R and C++, all within the friendly confines of RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-jared&#34;&gt;About Jared:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jared Lander is the Chief Data Scientist of Lander Analytics a data science consultancy based in New York City, the Organizer of the New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup and the New York R Conference and an Adjunct Professor of Statistics at Columbia University. With a masters from Columbia University in statistics and a bachelors from Muhlenberg College in mathematics, he has experience in both academic research and industry. His work for both large and small organizations ranges from music and fund raising to finance and humanitarian relief efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He specializes in data management, multilevel models, machine learning, generalized linear models, data management and statistical computing. He is the author of R for Everyone: Advanced Analytics and Graphics, a book about R Programming geared toward Data Scientists and Non-Statisticians alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: R Packages by Hadley Wickham</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-r-packages-by-hadley-wickham/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-r-packages-by-hadley-wickham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our next book club discussion! Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/254457098/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP. Bonus points if you try writing an R package and come to share your experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, October 20, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 2pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://r-pkgs.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R Packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Hadley Wickham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn OOP and discover cool finance packages in R</title>
      <link>/post/learn-oop-and-discover-cool-finance-packages-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learn-oop-and-discover-cool-finance-packages-in-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Two of our very own R-Ladies NYC board members will be speaking at our September Meetup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/254263203/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, September 18, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;: Soumya Kalra and Gabriela Hempfling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this event we will explore how to do OOP in R and learn the various use cases of the Performance Analytics Package in R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:45pm Introductions and Social&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:45-6:55pm R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:25pm Object Oriented Programming in R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:25-7:55pm Performance Analytics with R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:00pm Community Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:00-8:30pm Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;object-oriented-programming-in-r-moved-due-to-technical-difficulties-in-august&#34;&gt;Object Oriented Programming in R (Moved due to technical difficulties in August)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Soumya will provide an introduction to using these programming techniques in workflows and project development. She will primarily focus on building functions, S3 classes, as well as the most recent R6 classes. She will also provide the resources she used in her learning journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soumya is a quantitative analyst at the New York Federal Reserve where she focusing on developing models and tools as related to stress testing work. She is an organizer on the R-Ladies New York Board and on the committee for the R in Finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;performance-analytics-in-r&#34;&gt;Performance Analytics in R&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabby will introduce the PerformanceAnalytics package: a tool for performance and risk analysis on financial data. She will cover how to work with financial time series data in R, and useful metrics such as annualized return, standard deviation, sharpe ratios etc.
Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/PerformanceAnalytics/vignettes/PA-charts.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/PerformanceAnalytics/vignettes/PA-charts.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabby is a Financial Planning &amp;amp; Analysis associate at Two Sigma Investments. She learned R at Columbia in a datamining course and first employed it as an economic consultant analyzing the performance of loans underlying residential mortgage backed securities at NERA economic consulting. She is an organizer on the R-Ladies New York Board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Infrastructure with R</title>
      <link>/post/building-infrastructure-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-infrastructure-with-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/253219009/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Thursday, August 9, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;: Soumya Kalra and Emily Dodwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this event we will explore how to build tools and infrastructure with R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:15-6:30pm Introductions and Social&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30- 6:45 pm NYT announcements (Data, Tech, HR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:45-6:55pm R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:25pm Object Oriented Programming in R&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:25-7:55pm Big Data in R with Small Prototypes: Scaling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research Workflows from [/Local] to [Cloud/Cluster]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:00pm Community Announcements and News/Move to the 5th Floor for food/refreshments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:00-8:15pm Networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;object-oriented-programming-in-r&#34;&gt;Object Oriented Programming in R&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Soumya will provide an introduction to using these programming techniques in workflows and project development. She will primarily focus on building functions, S3 classes, as well as the most recent R6 classes. She will also provide the resources she used in her learning journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soumya is a quantitative analyst at the New York Federal Reserve where she focusing on developing models and tools as related to stress testing work. She is an organizer on the R-Ladies New York Board and on the committee for the R in Finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;big-data-in-r-with-small-prototypes-scaling-research-workflows-from-local-to-cloud-cluster&#34;&gt;Big Data in R with Small Prototypes: Scaling Research Workflows from [/Local] to [Cloud/Cluster]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk motivated by a recent project, Emily will discuss the tools her team at AT&amp;amp;T Labs explored when their typical workflow to process a data set and build a machine learning model in R would not scale due to the size of the data. She will provide some considerations for the data scientist faced with such a challenge, as well as a brief introduction to sparklyr. Created by the RStudio team, this package provides a dplyr interface to Spark from R, and thereby enables straightforward access to Spark’s distributed machine learning algorithms in MLlib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily is a Senior Inventive Scientist in the Statistics Research Department at AT&amp;amp;T Labs, where she currently focuses on predictive modeling for advertising applications and the creation of interactive tools for data analysis and visualization. She is a member of R Forwards &lt;a href=&#34;https://forwards.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://forwards.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;, the R Foundation taskforce on women and other under-represented groups. Prior to joining AT&amp;amp;T Labs in 2015, Emily taught high school math for three years at Choate Rosemary Hall. She received her M.A. in statistics from Yale University and B.A. in mathematics from Smith College.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning talks roundup</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks-roundup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first lightning talk event on Thursday June 14, 2018 at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oppenheimerfunds.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OppenheimerFunds&lt;/a&gt; was a huge success! We had a great diversity of speakers from different fields and with different backgrounds who gave talks on a wide variety of R-related topics. Below find a roundup of the lightning talks, including links to slides and videos of each talk. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OmmV4DKkgXTL5ljDNlIFDQYwupZBsL1cQH9TPXIZSvA/edit?ts=5b219b84#slide=id.p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breathing New Life into Old PowerPoint Templates: Kelly Dietz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798974924001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1XXkkRRgh7bmLWU8gvnsCETjE4N7IFsj39tE-LT4LcjU/edit#slide=id.p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art: Letisha Smith&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798967382001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1i-hlC07RDPvGm8GgmlwyD45MtUZhR7R32EgekRvlIZ0/edit#slide=id.g29c23c0132_0_21&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking the Data Science Interview: Learning from Both Sides of the Interview Table: Catherine Zhou&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798978032001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/Non-Representative Polls.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Representative Polls: Jennifer Kanjana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798970028001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1cm0AZxuobeR3rhGDkJGk7q0TjaNcTz14IGYUCZd2_ek/edit#slide=id.g35f391192_00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InteRactive: how to make your reports more engaging with R &amp;amp; Plotly: Gulya Radjapova&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798975622001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/Debugging Data in R - HF (1).html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging Data in R: Hannah Flaherty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798961539001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/sum_of_nothing.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sum of Nothing: R, Python pandas, and the different ways to do math with missing data: Christine Zhang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798961540001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/authors_lightning (1).html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Reads Whom: Text Mining Literary Interviews: Sarah Rankin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798974541001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/Rika Gorn slides.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Stories behind Missing Data: Policy and Practice in Social Services: Rika Gorn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798975807001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/r_ladies_five_mins (2).html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freak Your Factors: Luda Janda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798974542001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/R-Ladies Lightning Talk - Jahanshahi.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using R to Analyze Recruiting Pipelines: Maryam Jahanshahi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798970204001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1ShQPtCedKtcjvhM7HDXOuGCBD6Rt0skloumKAWaOBOY/edit#slide=id.p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reticulate: An R Interface to Python: Elizabeth Sweeney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798967383001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/satagopan-r-ladies-lightning-talk.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital data extraction using R and other tools: Jaya Satagopan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798974543001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/slides/rladies-lightning.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching the Tidyverse to Coworkers: Erin Grand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://players.brightcove.net/24488480001/r1QcbJ5Fx_default/index.html?videoId=5798975623001&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjana Guraziu: An RLady’s First R Conference</title>
      <link>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstats.nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New York R Conference&lt;/a&gt; was my first ever R conference, and it was great. I’ll write here about my experience, with links to resources from the widely varying talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I want to thank RLadiesNYC for the scholarship which allowed me to attend the conference. As a self-taught R newbie and incoming grad student, I greatly benefitted from attending this conference, and I so appreciate the opportunity from this great group! I would also like to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jaredlander.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jared Lander&lt;/a&gt; for his continued support of RLadies, and generosity in making opportunities like this possible. (Jared not only organizes this event, but also hosts regular meet-ups through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/nyhackr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup&lt;/a&gt; with presentations of past talks often available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nyhackr.org/presentations.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;–definitely check them out!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-conference&#34;&gt;The Conference&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/Hex Stickers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
NYR is a two-day conference that was held at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.work-bench.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Work-Bench&lt;/a&gt;. A few hundred people attended the sold-out conference, and they came from as far as San Francisco and London. It was great to meet the fellow attendees and to learn about the different fields that they worked in. I was initially nervous going into the conference and wondered if I could possibly keep up with the conversations. But I was pleasantly surprised at how easy and fun it was to chat with everyone. Everyone was very friendly and open: we were all there to hear about R and to meet and get to know other R users. So even if we shared very little in subject area, geography, or career path, I still had a great time talking to attendees about their work, my work, the talks, and what types of pizzas might be available for lunch. It was amazing to meet and interact with the speakers also - the people building the tools that we use every day and #rstats Twitter celebrities were not only giving talks, but also hanging out and trying to eat humongous ice cream sandwiches tidily like the rest of us. This interaction was facilitated by the great planning by Jared and team, from the casual attire to the frequent breaks with caffeine, snacks, and drinks always available. This opened up so many opportunities to meet and chat with new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-talks&#34;&gt;The Talks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/Screen Shot 2018-05-20 at 12.23.59 PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NYR had a very large range of talks: from R tips to statistics, from machine learning to implementing R in an organization, and so much more. For a quick overview of the talks, check out Daniel Chen’s compilation of notes from Brooke Watson and Mara Averick: &lt;a href=&#34;https://chendaniely.github.io/r/2018/04/22/rstatsnyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://chendaniely.github.io/r/2018/04/22/rstatsnyc/&lt;/a&gt;. Videos of all of the talks will be available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstats.nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NYR website&lt;/a&gt;, and past talks are already posted on the site so be sure to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most immediately applicable talk is probably &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/robinson_esv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emily Robinson’s&lt;/a&gt; the Lesser Known Stars of the Tidyverse. Emily’s talk was chock-full of tips and functions from Tidyverse tools that can be useful to your workflow. For example, if you print a large dataset it can take over your console. By using as_tibble() from the Tibble package, the first ten rows and only the columns that fit on your screen will print, making it much more manageable and still informative. For all of the tips, check out her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/secret/sMVjYvcd7yh16z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, and her &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robinsones/Data-Day-Talk/blob/master/data_day_script_accompanying.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in-depth document&lt;/a&gt; from an earlier talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most fun talks was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/evelgab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evelina Gabasova’s&lt;/a&gt; analysis of the Star Wars social network. Her &lt;a href=&#34;http://evelinag.com/blog/2015/12-15-star-wars-social-network/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; does an amazing job of analyzing the connectedness and centrality of characters from the movies, and suggests a hypothesis for why the prequels are just not as compelling as the original trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RLadiesNYC had great representation at the conference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brookLYNevery1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brooke Watson&lt;/a&gt; gave another super fun and informative talk about her package-development journey. In her &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Brooke-watson/nyr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.brooke.science/posts/scraping-javascript-websites-in-r/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; Brooke details how she first became inspired by the beepr package, which allows you to play a sound when a script is finished running. She built upon this idea with the BRRR package, which plays rap snippets. Two Emily’s represented, with aforementioned Emily Robinson and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zabormetrics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emily Zabor&lt;/a&gt;. Emily Zabor &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zabore/slidedecks/blob/master/nyr2018_zabor.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;taught us&lt;/a&gt; about survivor analysis in cancer research and how these prognoses are determined. As an incoming biostatistics student, I was very gratified to learn from Emily about this incredibly important topic in health research. Survival analysis is a complicated process, and has huge impacts on patients and families. But, Emily pointed out that this type of analysis is actually quite common: we are often curious about time-to-event endpoints in many contexts, like time to heart attack, time to onset of substance abuse, or time to machine malfunction. In all of these contexts it is important and difficult to get it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a sampling of the talks at NYR. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.revolutionanalytics.com/2018/04/minecraft-robot-in-r.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; to Machine Learning, it seemed like if there was any topic you were curious about it would be covered, and then some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rladies&#34;&gt;RLadies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/IMG_5347.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post would be sorely incomplete if I didn’t talk about the huge impact that RLadies has had on me. I learned about RLadies a little while ago, and initially wondered if it would be appropriate for me to go to an event. Did I know enough R? Would I be totally out of place? Then I went to a book club, where the conversation was interesting and the people were friendly and warm. I was hooked. I went to every event I could after that, and developed some kind and awesome new friendships. It made all the difference at my first R conference to already have friends from RLadiesNYC at the conference, and to have familiar faces to gravitate towards whenever I needed. To go along with my gratitude to RLadiesNYC, the most important thing to impart about this conference is how friendly it was. The R community in general is very friendly, with lots of encouragement and support available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/rstats?src=hash&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;community pages&lt;/a&gt;, and wherever else a learner might encounter fellow R users. This absolutely carries through in real life. I can&amp;rsquo;t emphasize enough how nice everyone was at NYR. Everyone was super approachable, from attendees to speakers, and this made the learning a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R is an awesome language, but I wouldn’t be this excited about it if I weren’t so excited about the people that are in this community. NYR was a great conference that really highlighted the strength of the R community. A telling example of this is the community&amp;rsquo;s constant drive to improve. As Brooke Watson commented, it was very exciting that there was now a line for the women&amp;rsquo;s bathroom! Indeed, gender diversity among speakers was better than many other technical conferences I’ve seen. However, as was highlighted by Emily Robinson, diversity is a big ongoing effort and the community is trying to improve it in the coming years. RLadies in particular is committed to increasing diversity in general in the R community, and welcome any ideas to this end. This conscientiousness and the general warmth of the R community give me full confidence that great strides will be made, and I can’t wait to attend NYR again in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Artificial Unintelligence</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our next book club discussion! This book club event will include a very special appearance by the author, Meredith Broussard, so don&amp;rsquo;t miss out. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/251676940/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, July 14, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 11am&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/artificial-unintelligence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence: How Computers Misunderstand the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Meredith Broussard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks!</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; lineup of speakers giving lightning talks! These talks are 5 minutes in length on a wide variety of R and data science topics. Come learn from your peers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:55: Food &amp;amp; Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:00: Introduction by our host&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:00-8:30: Lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:30-9:00: Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talks and speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using R to Analyze Recruiting Pipelines: Maryam Jahanshahi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freak Your Factors: Luda Janda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art: Letisha Smith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital data extraction using R and other tools: Jaya Satagopan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reticulate: An R Interface to Python: Elizabeth Sweeney&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who Reads Whom: Text Mining Literary Interviews: Sarah Rankin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaching the Tidyverse to Coworkers: Erin Grand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InteRactive: how to make your reports more engaging with R &amp;amp; Plotly: Gulya Radjapova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging Data in R: Hannah Flaherty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sum of Nothing: R, Python pandas, and the different ways to do math with missing data: Christine Zhang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Representative Polls: Jennifer Kanjana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathing New Life into Old PowerPoint Templates: Kelly Dietz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stories behind Missing Data: Policy and Practice in Social Services: Rika Gorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cracking the Data Science Interview: Learning from Both Sides of the Interview Table: Catherine Zhou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/250824638/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, June 14, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oppenheimerfunds.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OppenheimerFunds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
