<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies NYC on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hex Sticker Result</title>
      <link>/post/hex-sticker-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hex-sticker-result/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R-Ladies NYC call for a hex sticker design produced three creative and unique submissions. We would like to thank Ayanthi Gunawardana, Kat Hoffman, and Ludmila Janda for their involvement with the R-Ladies NYC community and time spent crafting their designs! Below, each of these R-Ladies shares her inspiration behind her design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/ayanthi.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HoneyBadger88&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ayanthi Gunawardana&lt;/a&gt;: My goal was the keep the logo and colors as simple as possible to ensure it could be scaled to any size. I saw the negative space in the bottom of the &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; and immediately knew I wanted to use it creatively for the logo. I picked NYC landmarks that would fit in that space and ordered them in decreasing height to make sure it still looked like the letter &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/kat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rkatlady&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kat Hoffman&lt;/a&gt;: I moved to New York last August and immediately realized one of my favorite activities—besides attending R-Ladies events, of course!—was walking around the city to look at all the amazing street art. I tried to emulate this urban uniqueness in my design while emphasizing inclusivity (rainbow color scheme) and iconic NYC (Statue of Liberty crown over “Ladies”). I really enjoyed learning Adobe Illustrator to make my submission, and I am looking forward to representing R-Ladies in ggplot form on my laptop soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/luda.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ludmila_janda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ludmila Janda&lt;/a&gt;: I was inspired by our city and wanted to find a way use data and R for the sticker so I got the heights of several iconic structures and their spires and made a graph with ggplot. Then I used google drawings to make buildings and laid them over the graph to make the final image, which I used with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuangchuangYu/hexSticker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hexSticker package&lt;/a&gt; for the final product. Many thanks to Guangchuang Yu for quickly closing my issue (#62) for his package in order to let the URL angle vary as parameter - I used that for the &amp;ldquo;NYC&amp;rdquo; part of the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Ludmila Janda! Her design was chosen as the winner in a tight Twitter poll on June 20th. Please join us at future R-Ladies NYC events for your opportunity to snag a new hex sticker and represent our chapter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-07-03-hex-sticker-result/poll.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come hang out with R-Ladies at the Royale Bar outdoor patio for an afternoon social full of fun, board games, and splendid R conversation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinks and food will be available for purchase. Collaborative, multi-player and two-player table games will be provided, but feel free to bring your own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, July 13, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm - 5:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Royale, 157 Loisaida Ave, New York, NY, 10009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/262478374/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and Fantasy Baseball?</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you so much to Anisha BharathSingh, who originally wrote this post for her blog, found &lt;a href=&#34;https://journeytodatascientist.blog/2019/05/24/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We are reposting her post with her consent. If you are an R-Lady interested in writing a blog post or cross-posting a blog post on your own blog, please let us know (via email nyc@rladies.org or via DM on twitter @RLadiesNYC)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, May 23, I attended my first R-Ladies NYC meetup! R-Ladies NYC is an organization that promotes gender diversity amongst the R community by organizing a series of events (including this meetup) to support women who want to learn R or want to share their experiences as R programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drafting-a-fantasy-baseball-team-with-r&#34;&gt;Drafting a Fantasy Baseball Team with R&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meetup included an interesting take on data science – using R to draft a fantasy baseball team! This was presented by Angeline Protacio, a self-employed data scientist at Protacio Analytics LLC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, Angeline spends her time playing fantasy baseball. For those not familiar with fantasy baseball, as Angeline explained, you create your own fantasy baseball team with real players from any existing team. Each day, you decide what your lineup will be, and how well your team does depends on each players actual performance that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angeline wanted to use her data science skills to draft a competitive fantasy baseball team. To do so, Angeline used a series of &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.mlb.com/glossary/standard-stats&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;player scoring categories&lt;/a&gt; including: R, HR, RBI, SO, SB, OPS, WAR. She first took a look at how a player’s position affected their scoring categories with ggplot visualizations. From this, she found that outfielders had better offensive stats and suggests to draft your outfielders first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Metric Comparing Overall Performance for Players&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, in order to determine which specific players to draft, Angeline tried looking for a summary statistic of all scoring categories to compare all players to each other, but could not find any. While there is the WAR (Wins Above Replacement) scoring category that summarizes a players contribution to their team, this only does so with respect to being substituted by a replacement player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led her to creating her own metric. With the help of the tidyverse package she: 1) filtered for players who had an average plate appearance above 300; 2) selected player id, position, Name, Team and all scoring categories; and 3) mutated her data frame with the players information to include a z-score for each scoring category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This z-score is used to determine how much better a player performed than the mean for that category. Summing these z-scores provided an overall performance metric for each player in comparison to all other players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top MLB Players of 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using her new metric, Angeline arranged her new data frame in a descending order to find the Top 5 MLB players for 2018:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Trout (Angels) – total z-score: 11.889&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giancarlo Stanton (Yankees) – total z-score: 11.869&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nolan Arenado (Rockies) – total z-score: 8.766&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryce Harper (Phillies) – total z-score: 8.646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthony Rizzo (Cubs) – total z-score: 8.343&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angelinepro/rladiesnyc_may2019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; for the repository with all of Angeline’s code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this only accounts for one part of drafting a fantasy baseball team, this just goes to show that you can use data science for pretty much anything!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are hosting a very special event - lightning talks from the R-Ladies community! Come out to hear a variety of R &amp;amp; Data Science talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Wednesday, June 19, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:00pm - 9:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: A whole lot of R ladies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: OppenheimerFunds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Elizbeth Sweeny&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/262079485/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYR 2019 Speaker Experience and Tips</title>
      <link>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-05-28-nyr-conference-tips/stickers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New York R conference attracts a diverse yet technical audience which means the bar is high for all invited speakers. This year, over half the speakers were women, including several R-Ladies NYC members. It was such a fun and good experience that we decided to collaborate and write a blog post to encourage others to speak at conferences and provide some tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Ludmila Janda, Emily Robinson, Emily Dodwell, Gabriela Hempfling, Elizabeth Sweeny, Soumya Kalra, Brooke Watson, Amanda Dobbyn, Letisha Smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips-on-speaking&#34;&gt;Tips on Speaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Summarize your talk to someone you know well but isn’t too familiar with the subject matter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice a couple times. If your team at work is willing, schedule time to give your talk several days or a week before the conference. Ludmila’s team listened to her talk twice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take deep breaths before you get on stage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anyone raises their hand and then starts talking in the middle of your talk just say “I’m sorry we aren’t taking any questions” and keep it moving! Don’t let them get you out of your flow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people look like they’re frowning when they’re trying to listen. Don’t be distracted by reading too much into their expressions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have fun on stage and don’t get embarrassed during your walk out song&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the speakers&amp;rsquo; lounge to prepare and decompress&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks can be a great way to practice! They are five minute talks in front of a smaller audience that can help you get the format down and trial run an idea. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeJom9L9SBqYPr0gU_GVwPXPvYqv167tLafrv2SaBJYvXJK7Q/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;You can submit a talk for the upcoming R-Ladies NYC lightning talks event here!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rladiesnyc.org/post/lightning-talks-roundup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s lightning talks can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hookedondata.org/giving-your-first-data-science-talk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More tips from Emily Robinson on her blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to R-ladies for support and feedback before giving a talk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, one of the hardest things about giving a talk is getting yourself to start preparing your slides. Sometimes, it can feel hard to even choose what to use to make the slides. Therefore, we are including a section on what we used to make our slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerpoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As timeless as Michael Scott, there’s no shame in “Powerpoint, Powerpoint, Powerpoint”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be helpful even if you want to just storyboard the idea first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Gabriela, Emily R, Elizabeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keynote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerpoint for Millenials™&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rumored to be used by Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Brooke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xaringan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cool newish package in R!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits: you can easily make your slides in R and immediately see updates to the slides, easily incorporate talk notes, includes a presentation mode with a timer, formats slides very easily and nicely, allows you to experiment with interesting themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawbacks: Has a bit of learning curve, can be a bit buggy (sometimes having the immediate viewing of changes on can really slow down ability to edit the slides), it was a bit hard to deal with unmirroring the display and dragging one set of slides to the big screen, not as easy as using presenter mode in something like powerpoint, but if you don’t need notes there is no need to worry about this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Ludmila, Amanda, and Soumya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits: Google slides makes it very easy to create beautiful slides with the Explore feature. If you type text or paste an image on the slide, Google will automatically recommend 10 ways to better format the slide. Plus, using the Google Slides app makes it very easy to practice your presentation during your commute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawback: While Google supports version control with the Version History feature, it does not allow reproducible research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used by: Letisha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;walk-out-music&#34;&gt;Walk out Music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NYR has a fun tradition of letting the speaker pick a song to walk out to, but this can feel like a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; decision. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the song only plays for about 10 - 20 seconds and it might not start right where you would want it to, even if you give a specific time to start the song. These were our walk out songs this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludmila Janda (Building the Tidyverse From Scratch: Teaching Data Cleaning and Visualization with R-inspired Custom Scratch Blocks): Mi Gente - J Balvin, Willy William, Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Dodwell (From Tangled Lassos to Boosted Trees: Iterative Research in Practice): Run the World (Girls) - Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Robinson (Everything You Wanted to Know About Making R Packages but Were Afraid to Ask): Mrs. Robinson, Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabriela Hempfling (I’ll Have What She’s Having (and Other Models of Consumer Behavior): Bad Bad News - Leon Bridges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Sweeny (Neuroimaging Analysis in R): Insane in the Brain - Cypress Hill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soumya Kalra (Becoming a better finance practitioner): Forget my name - Danko Jones&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brooke Watson (Using R to defend immigrant&amp;rsquo;s rights at the ACLU): Freedom - Beyonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda Dobbyn (This Talk is on Fire: Using Twitter and Google to Track Fires in NYC): We Didn’t Start the Fire, Billy Joel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letisha Smith (Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art): I&amp;rsquo;m Every Woman - Chaka Khan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/0VAHe4mcJDB5iWBgypMq2X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tech Ladies&lt;/a&gt; playlist also has a lot of empowering singles to choose from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2019-05-28-nyr-conference-tips/rladies.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to discuss &lt;strong&gt;How Not To Be Wrong&lt;/strong&gt; by Jordan Ellenberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, May 25th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/261214466/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request for 2019 Lightning Talk Submissions</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talk-submissions-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talk-submissions-request/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies NYC are excited to be hosting an evening of lightning talks on Wednesday June 19! We held this event last year and it was a tremendous success, so we are really excited about the event this year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lighting talks are five minute talks. You can talk about anything R, Tech, and/or Data Science related. Looking for ideas? How about talking about a cool package you found, how you use R in your company, a favorite learning resource, your journey into Data Science, or a side project you&amp;rsquo;ve been working on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would especially love to hear from people who&amp;rsquo;ve never presented at a meetup or conference before and/or those who still don&amp;rsquo;t feel confident public speaking. A lightning talk can be a great way to start out speaking, as it&amp;rsquo;s quick, low-prep, and fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in proposing a talk but want to brainstorm ideas, get feedback, or some encouragement? We&amp;rsquo;re here to help! You can join the #lightningtalks channel in our slack channel or email nyc@rladies.org. We would be happy to set up a time to talk with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the diversity in the R Community, we&amp;rsquo;re limiting presenters to those who identify as a minority gender (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeJom9L9SBqYPr0gU_GVwPXPvYqv167tLafrv2SaBJYvXJK7Q/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Please submit talk proposals here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request for R-Ladies Logo Submissions</title>
      <link>/post/request-for-r-ladies-logo-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/request-for-r-ladies-logo-submissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that we are holding open submissions for an R-Ladies NYC logo for hex stickers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design notes: the R-Ladies font is Open Sans and the colors are #88398a (Purple) &amp;amp; #a7a9ac (Gray), though the logo can use variants of these colors and other colors. Here is the repo for the R-Ladies logo as a reference. Also, the hexSticker package is useful, but you are welcome to use any tool you desire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email your submissions to nyc@rladies.org with the subject line &amp;ldquo;hex sticker design&amp;rdquo;. We will hold a public vote for the logo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples for inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://community.rstudio.com/uploads/default/original/2X/e/e3d6e7312a2e01e0fae8ee76d9d3ccaebe902b83.jpeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R-Ladies Austin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/8/0/8/b/600_476852907.jpeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R-Ladies CDMX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/5/3/a/8/600_480981416.jpeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R-Ladies Xalapa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Journeys and Fantasy Baseball with R</title>
      <link>/post/getting-into-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-into-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Angeline and Kaelen will discuss their transition into Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, May 23rd, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Angeline Protacio and Kaelen Medeiros&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: JP Morgan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event Organizer: Emily Robinson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/261228248/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/r-package-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-package-workshop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bring your laptop and come out to our next workshop to learn about building your very own R package!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/259858458/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s workshop will focus on R package development from the ground up. We will cover package structure, set-up, creating functions, documentation, testing, dependencies, sharing the package with others, package vignettes, hex stickers, and other methods. An example package will be developed during the workshop so attendees can follow along and create their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Zabor and Erin Grand are also going to be serving has TAs for this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, March 26, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: Vroom (1375 Broadway Ave, 11th floor)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sebastian-s-bio&#34;&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian is a data scientist at Vroom, an ecommerce start-up that focuses on selling used cars that are delivered to your door. Previously, Sebastian was doing research on cancer genomics as a postdoc at Yale University. He has also been a strong advocate for R-Ladies and is an experienced CRAN package author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Seborinos/rladiesnyc_package_workshop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Pipelines with Text and Data</title>
      <link>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are excited this month to host two very active R-Ladies from our chapter: Amanda Dobbyn and Maryam Jahanshahi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/258458666/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesday, February 12, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 6:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt; WeWork (205 Hudson S)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda&amp;rsquo;s talk will focus on the package &amp;lsquo;drake&amp;rsquo;. &lt;code&gt;Drake&lt;/code&gt; is a package designed to make designing and executing analysis pipelines easier and more reproducible. In this talk Amanda will run through an example of how &lt;code&gt;drake&lt;/code&gt; can be used to manage an analysis workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryam&amp;rsquo;s talk will focus on designing and executing text processing pipelines. In this talk, Maryam will share lessons and takeaways on text processing and data management for natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amanda-s-bio&#34;&gt;Amanda&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda is a data scientist at Earlybird Software, a cloud application and data consulting company. She was previously an organizer of R-Ladies Chicago before escaping that frozen tundra for this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maryam-s-bio&#34;&gt;Maryam&amp;rsquo;s Bio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryam is a Research Scientist at TapRecruit, a software startup that helps companies improve the fairness and efficiency of their recruiting processes. In a past life, Maryam was a cancer biologist and a data journalist. In a future life, Maryam hopes to be a carpenter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Arrival and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6:30-7:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Talks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30-8pm&lt;/strong&gt;: Networking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Algorithms to live by</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At our next book club meeting, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss Algorithms to Live By, by Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/257130300/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please support our wonderful host bookstore, Rizzoli, by ordering the book directly from them &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/algorithms-live-computer-science-human-decisions-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;through this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt; Saturday, January 26, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt; Rizzoli Bookstore (1133 Broadway Ave)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git with Joyce</title>
      <link>/post/git-with-joyce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-with-joyce/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are kicking off this year with an introduction to Github by Joyce Robbins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/257698665/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hands on workshop so please bring your laptop to follow along and please be prompt to make sure the workshop kicks off on time:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Wednesday, January 9, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: Columbia University (1255 Amsterdam Ave, Room 903)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-joyce&#34;&gt;About Joyce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joyce Robbins, Ph.D., is Lecturer in Discipline in the Statistics Department at Columbia University, where she specializes in data visualization. She is a member of the R Forwards (R Foundation taskforce on women and other under-represented groups) teaching team, and elected to serve as publications officer of the Statistical Graphics Section of the American Statistical Association Section beginning in 2018. Robbins received her doctorate in sociology from Columbia University, her M.A. in sociology and anthropology from Tel Aviv University and her B.S.E. in civil engineering and operations research from Princeton University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Joyce&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found at their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jtr13/codehelp/blob/master/GitHubWorkflow.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 End of Year Social</title>
      <link>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays! For the end of the year we are looking to celebrate how far R-Ladies New York has come and thank all of you for your incredible support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/256736860/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are doing this potluck style so &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ytU6boa7oDAM3gujH0NRIy9ezS03P4Q4BWx6v6StIcY/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to bring something to the party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dress in casual or holiday gear - we welcome it all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Monday, December 10, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center (33 Thomas Street New York, NY)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility and Communication in R</title>
      <link>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This month it is our pleasure to have Noam Ross and our very own Ludmila Janda present on Reproducibility and Communication in R!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/255925263/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, November 6, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;: The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:45pm - General networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:45-6:55pm - R-Ladies New York Announcements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:25pm - Reproducibility in an Office World: A Brief History of Failures and the Odd Success by Noam Ross&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:25-7:55pm A Data Odyssey: Communicating Results With Coworkers
by Ludamila Janda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55-8:00pm R-Ladies Community announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:00-8:30pm Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reproducibility-in-an-office-world-a-brief-history-of-failures-and-the-odd-success&#34;&gt;Reproducibility in an Office World: A Brief History of Failures and the Odd Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many data scientists operate at the interface of two cultures with different tools and workflows - programmatic workflows (e.g., R Markdown) and WYSIWYG documents (e.g., Microsoft Word). The noisy interface between these can be an impediment to reproducibility, as well as a royal pain. I will discuss approaches I and others have tried in dealing with these issues, and why and how some have failed and succeeded. I&amp;rsquo;ll also demonstrate some tools, including packages officer and rvg and some rarely used feaures of rmarkdown that ease the flow when collaborating across the divide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noam Ross is a Senior Research Scientist at EcoHealth Alliance, a non-profit in NYC that researches the connections between human and wildlife health. Noam builds models to understand and predict disease circulation in wildlife and spillover into people. Noam is also editor for software peer review at rOpenSci, a developer collective that builds R packages and catalyzes communities to enable open research and data. He has a Ph.D. in ecology from the University of California-Davis. Follow him on twitter at @noamross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Noam&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noamross/2018-11-06-rladies-talk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Noam&amp;rsquo;s GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-data-odyssey-communicating-results-with-coworkers&#34;&gt;A Data Odyssey: Communicating Results With Coworkers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, data scientists are tasked with communicating their results with people in the workplace who do not share the same technical background. Bridging the gaps between parties can be a perilous journey. In this talk, I will discuss how I have attempted to navigate this tricky terrain and provide some pointers for clear language use and data visualization choices. I’ll demonstrate how I pass on insights through visualizations using packages such as ggridges and ggalluvial and how I use rmarkdown to craft reports and take my coworkers on data adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludmila Janda is a Data Scientist at Amplify, a pioneer in K–12 education since 2000, leading the way in next-generation curriculum and assessment. Today, Amplify serves four million students in all 50 states. Luda’s work provides insights on student and teacher usage, student success, and Amplify’s broader impact. She is a proud RLady and has a Master’s in Public Policy from the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill. Follow her on twitter at @ludmila_janda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides from Ludmila&amp;rsquo;s talk can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ljanda/rladiesnyc_talk_11_06_2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ludmila&amp;rsquo;s GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
