<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjana Guraziu: An RLady’s First R Conference</title>
      <link>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstats.nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New York R Conference&lt;/a&gt; was my first ever R conference, and it was great. I’ll write here about my experience, with links to resources from the widely varying talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I want to thank RLadiesNYC for the scholarship which allowed me to attend the conference. As a self-taught R newbie and incoming grad student, I greatly benefitted from attending this conference, and I so appreciate the opportunity from this great group! I would also like to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jaredlander.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jared Lander&lt;/a&gt; for his continued support of RLadies, and generosity in making opportunities like this possible. (Jared not only organizes this event, but also hosts regular meet-ups through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/nyhackr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup&lt;/a&gt; with presentations of past talks often available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nyhackr.org/presentations.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;–definitely check them out!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-conference&#34;&gt;The Conference&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/Hex Stickers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
NYR is a two-day conference that was held at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.work-bench.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Work-Bench&lt;/a&gt;. A few hundred people attended the sold-out conference, and they came from as far as San Francisco and London. It was great to meet the fellow attendees and to learn about the different fields that they worked in. I was initially nervous going into the conference and wondered if I could possibly keep up with the conversations. But I was pleasantly surprised at how easy and fun it was to chat with everyone. Everyone was very friendly and open: we were all there to hear about R and to meet and get to know other R users. So even if we shared very little in subject area, geography, or career path, I still had a great time talking to attendees about their work, my work, the talks, and what types of pizzas might be available for lunch. It was amazing to meet and interact with the speakers also - the people building the tools that we use every day and #rstats Twitter celebrities were not only giving talks, but also hanging out and trying to eat humongous ice cream sandwiches tidily like the rest of us. This interaction was facilitated by the great planning by Jared and team, from the casual attire to the frequent breaks with caffeine, snacks, and drinks always available. This opened up so many opportunities to meet and chat with new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-talks&#34;&gt;The Talks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/Screen Shot 2018-05-20 at 12.23.59 PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NYR had a very large range of talks: from R tips to statistics, from machine learning to implementing R in an organization, and so much more. For a quick overview of the talks, check out Daniel Chen’s compilation of notes from Brooke Watson and Mara Averick: &lt;a href=&#34;https://chendaniely.github.io/r/2018/04/22/rstatsnyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://chendaniely.github.io/r/2018/04/22/rstatsnyc/&lt;/a&gt;. Videos of all of the talks will be available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstats.nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NYR website&lt;/a&gt;, and past talks are already posted on the site so be sure to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most immediately applicable talk is probably &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/robinson_esv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emily Robinson’s&lt;/a&gt; the Lesser Known Stars of the Tidyverse. Emily’s talk was chock-full of tips and functions from Tidyverse tools that can be useful to your workflow. For example, if you print a large dataset it can take over your console. By using as_tibble() from the Tibble package, the first ten rows and only the columns that fit on your screen will print, making it much more manageable and still informative. For all of the tips, check out her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/secret/sMVjYvcd7yh16z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, and her &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robinsones/Data-Day-Talk/blob/master/data_day_script_accompanying.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in-depth document&lt;/a&gt; from an earlier talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most fun talks was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/evelgab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evelina Gabasova’s&lt;/a&gt; analysis of the Star Wars social network. Her &lt;a href=&#34;http://evelinag.com/blog/2015/12-15-star-wars-social-network/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; does an amazing job of analyzing the connectedness and centrality of characters from the movies, and suggests a hypothesis for why the prequels are just not as compelling as the original trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RLadiesNYC had great representation at the conference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brookLYNevery1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brooke Watson&lt;/a&gt; gave another super fun and informative talk about her package-development journey. In her &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Brooke-watson/nyr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.brooke.science/posts/scraping-javascript-websites-in-r/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; Brooke details how she first became inspired by the beepr package, which allows you to play a sound when a script is finished running. She built upon this idea with the BRRR package, which plays rap snippets. Two Emily’s represented, with aforementioned Emily Robinson and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zabormetrics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emily Zabor&lt;/a&gt;. Emily Zabor &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zabore/slidedecks/blob/master/nyr2018_zabor.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;taught us&lt;/a&gt; about survivor analysis in cancer research and how these prognoses are determined. As an incoming biostatistics student, I was very gratified to learn from Emily about this incredibly important topic in health research. Survival analysis is a complicated process, and has huge impacts on patients and families. But, Emily pointed out that this type of analysis is actually quite common: we are often curious about time-to-event endpoints in many contexts, like time to heart attack, time to onset of substance abuse, or time to machine malfunction. In all of these contexts it is important and difficult to get it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a sampling of the talks at NYR. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.revolutionanalytics.com/2018/04/minecraft-robot-in-r.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; to Machine Learning, it seemed like if there was any topic you were curious about it would be covered, and then some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rladies&#34;&gt;RLadies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2018-06-27-an-rladys-first-r-conference/IMG_5347.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post would be sorely incomplete if I didn’t talk about the huge impact that RLadies has had on me. I learned about RLadies a little while ago, and initially wondered if it would be appropriate for me to go to an event. Did I know enough R? Would I be totally out of place? Then I went to a book club, where the conversation was interesting and the people were friendly and warm. I was hooked. I went to every event I could after that, and developed some kind and awesome new friendships. It made all the difference at my first R conference to already have friends from RLadiesNYC at the conference, and to have familiar faces to gravitate towards whenever I needed. To go along with my gratitude to RLadiesNYC, the most important thing to impart about this conference is how friendly it was. The R community in general is very friendly, with lots of encouragement and support available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/rstats?src=hash&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;community pages&lt;/a&gt;, and wherever else a learner might encounter fellow R users. This absolutely carries through in real life. I can&amp;rsquo;t emphasize enough how nice everyone was at NYR. Everyone was super approachable, from attendees to speakers, and this made the learning a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R is an awesome language, but I wouldn’t be this excited about it if I weren’t so excited about the people that are in this community. NYR was a great conference that really highlighted the strength of the R community. A telling example of this is the community&amp;rsquo;s constant drive to improve. As Brooke Watson commented, it was very exciting that there was now a line for the women&amp;rsquo;s bathroom! Indeed, gender diversity among speakers was better than many other technical conferences I’ve seen. However, as was highlighted by Emily Robinson, diversity is a big ongoing effort and the community is trying to improve it in the coming years. RLadies in particular is committed to increasing diversity in general in the R community, and welcome any ideas to this end. This conscientiousness and the general warmth of the R community give me full confidence that great strides will be made, and I can’t wait to attend NYR again in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Artificial Unintelligence</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our next book club discussion! This book club event will include a very special appearance by the author, Meredith Broussard, so don&amp;rsquo;t miss out. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/251676940/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, July 14, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 11am&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/artificial-unintelligence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence: How Computers Misunderstand the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Meredith Broussard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks!</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; lineup of speakers giving lightning talks! These talks are 5 minutes in length on a wide variety of R and data science topics. Come learn from your peers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30-6:55: Food &amp;amp; Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:55-7:00: Introduction by our host&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:00-8:30: Lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:30-9:00: Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talks and speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzing Recruiting Pipelines with R: Maryam Jahanshahi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freak Your Factors: Luda Janda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art: Letisha Smith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital data extraction using R and other tools: Jaya Satagopan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reticulate: An R Interface to Python: Elizabeth Sweeney&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who Reads Whom: Text Mining Literary Interviews: Sarah Rankin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaching the Tidyverse to Coworkers: Erin Grand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InteRactive: make your analyses &amp;amp; reports more engaging with R &amp;amp; Plotly: Gulya Radjapova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging Data in R: Hannah Flaherty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sum of Nothing: R, Python pandas, and the different ways to do math with missing data: Christine Zhang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Representative Polls: Jennifer Kanjana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathing New Life into Old PowerPoint Templates: Kelly Dietz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stories behind Missing Data: Policy and Practice in Social Services: Rika Gorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title TBD: Catherine Zhou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/250824638/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, June 14, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oppenheimerfunds.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OppenheimerFunds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Shiny Apps using NBA data</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-shiny-apps-using-nba-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-shiny-apps-using-nba-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out for our May event for a tutorial on Shiny! Julia Wrobel, a PhD candidate in biostatistics at Columbia University, will be teaching us to make and deploy Shiny apps using NBA data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The materials for this talk can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;http://juliawrobel.com/tutorials/shiny_tutorial_nba.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Julia&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your laptops so that you can code as you go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/249873160/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, May 8, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Julia Wrobel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: NBA NYC Office&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Storytelling with Data</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-storytelling-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-storytelling-with-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our next book club discussion! Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/249296340/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, April 28, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 3pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/storytelling-data-data-visualization-guide-business-professionals&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;STORYTELLING WITH DATA: A DATA VISUALIZATION GUIDE FOR BUSINESS PROFESSIONALS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy evaluation: Programming with ggplot2 and dplyr</title>
      <link>/post/tidy-evaluation-programming-with-ggplot2-and-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidy-evaluation-programming-with-ggplot2-and-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this month&amp;rsquo;s meetup we have a very special guest : Hadley Wickham!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/249296205/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, April 19, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Hadley Wickham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twosigma.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Two Sigma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelization of Simulations with the foreach Package and Missing Data in R</title>
      <link>/post/parallelization-foreach-and-missing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallelization-foreach-and-missing-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to our March event to hear talks from two great R Ladies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we&amp;rsquo;ll learn about parallelization of simulations with the foreach R package, with applications to progression free survival assessed using electronic health records. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll get an introduction to methods for handling missing data in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/247926543/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, March 20, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Elizabeth Sweeney and Mine Dogucu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://flatiron.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flatiron Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating websites in R</title>
      <link>/post/creating-websites-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-websites-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to create a blog or website to share your work or ideas? Join us for a tutorial on creating websites in R! Emily Zabor will cover the basics of creating a website or blog in R. After the tutorial, Daniela Vazquez of R Ladies Buenos Aires and Montevideo, will give us a one-year update on her transition to a data science career. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/247304067/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the materials for this tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emilyzabor.com/tutorials/rmarkdown_websites_tutorial.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, February 15, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Emily Zabor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.research.att.com/editions/201704_home.html?fbid=zhT-ct1cN_d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Functional Programming with Purrr</title>
      <link>/post/workshop-functional-programming-with-purrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workshop-functional-programming-with-purrr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our first R Ladies NYC event of 2018!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joyce Robbins presents a workshop on the purrr package, a complete and coherent packae for working with functions and vectors in R. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/242371329/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joyce&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo for this talk can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jtr13/RLadies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Wednesday, January 10, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructor: Joyce Robbins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: Schapiro Center Columbia University&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jasmine Williams: My first step to healing from WISDOM (Women in Stats, Data Science, and Omics)</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-step-to-healing-from-wisdom-women-in-stats-data-science-and-omics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-step-to-healing-from-wisdom-women-in-stats-data-science-and-omics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it grew nearer to the fall season my heart and mind grew heavier. This was the first birthday and holiday gatherings without grandma. I became distant from everything outside of my family and work, and knew I had to get out of this emotional funk. The 2017 Women in Statistics and Data Science conference brought together hundreds of data scientists and statisticians from all walks of life in an intimate setting to share their personal and professional experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it just in time for Dr. Susmita Datta’s “Making Your Mark” opening remarks where she shared her journey to becoming a statistician working in academia. Not everything in her story seemed as glamorous as her resume/CV but it didn’t make her story unworthy to be told. A balanced mix of sacrifices and risks were taken for Dr. Datta to be who she is, what she is, and where she is today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Use your fear to grow”, “Open heart, open mind”, and “Don’t be afraid to take a risk to modify your goals” are a few of the #motivationalmonday mantras I mentally collected and stored from my overall experience at WSDS. Most of these, if not all, are mantras that we all live by to figure life out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandmother wasn’t a R-Lady, statistician, data scientist, epidemiologist, or any –gists for that matter. But she was a woman that took risks that brought her out of the comfort zone; she used her fear (young widowed mother) to grow in order to raise her children and grandchildren, and inspired her friends, family, and family-friends to have an open heart and mind approach to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so fortunate to be part of R-Ladies that showcases the WSDS17 motto: knowledge, community, and influence (WSDS17 Motto). We all have hardships but it so important to push yourself and so as we enter 2018 let’s push.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon!</title>
      <link>/post/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned in 2018 for the R-Ladies NYC blog, which will feature guest bloggers from the R-Ladies NYC community. Interested in writing a blog post? Contact us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nyc@rladies.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nyc@rladies.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Everybody Lies</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-everybody-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-everybody-lies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for our first book club discussion of 2018! Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/245465157/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, January 20, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 3pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/everybody-lies-big-data-new-data-and-what-internet-can-tell-us-about-who-we-really-are-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Everybody Lies: Big Data, New Data, and What the Internet Can Tell Us About Who We Really Are&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Seth Stephens-Davidowitz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in the World of Education</title>
      <link>/post/r-in-the-world-of-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-in-the-world-of-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our last event of 2017!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin Grand will speak about how she uses R in the World of Eduction. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/245064725/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo for this event can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eringrand/eringrand.github.io/tree/rawbranch/Presentations/rladies-nyc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, December 12, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Erin Grand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.research.att.com/editions/201704_home.html?fbid=zhT-ct1cN_d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Dive Night with Data for Democracy</title>
      <link>/post/data-dive-night-with-data-for-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-dive-night-with-data-for-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get together with our laptops and R skills and code to continue to explore Medicare spending data. Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/242471496/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 24, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quartethealth.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quartet Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Truth or Truthiness</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-truth-or-truthiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-truth-or-truthiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come join us for a discussion for our next book club discussion! Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-newyork/events/242382626/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; page for more details and to RSVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday, September 30, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time: 12pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/truth-or-truthiness-distinguishing-fact-fiction-learning-think-data-scientist&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Truth or Truthiness: Distinguishing Fact from Fiction by Learning to Think Like a Data Scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Howard Wainer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rizzolibookstore.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rizzoli Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
