<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Gender Bias with R</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-gender-bias-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analyzing-gender-bias-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Details For our October event, R-Ladies Yipeng Lai and Stacy Lansey will share short talks on using R for analyzing gender bias on Wikipedia and learning R through data visualization (which motivated an interesting side project on gender).
This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page at noon on the day of the event.
Agenda (times approximate): 7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements 7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Text Analysis in R: Gender Bias in Wikipedia Biographies&amp;rdquo; by Yipeng Lai 7:30-7:55: &amp;ldquo;R is for Resilience: Learning R through Data Visualization&amp;rdquo; by Stacy Lansey 7:55-8:15: Questions and wrap-up</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-charts-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-charts-lie/</guid>
      <description>Details For our September book club, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing &amp;ldquo;How Charts Lie: Getting Smarter about Visual Information&amp;rdquo; by Alberto Cairo.
Zoom link will be available to attendees on the Meetup event page as of 9 am Eastern on September 26th.
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies NYC Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks-2020/</guid>
      <description>We are hosting a very special event - lightning talks from the R-Ladies community! Come out to hear a variety of R and Data Science talks.
This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.
Agenda: 7-7:05: Welcome and R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-8:30: Lightning Talks!
Talks and Speakers:  &amp;ldquo;Partial Correlation Networks in R&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Erin McDonnell &amp;ldquo;Batch Production of Reports in RMarkdown&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Alyssa Goldberg &amp;ldquo;Time Series Analysis of Bird Migrations Above NYC Skies Using bioRad&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Mei Guan &amp;ldquo;Webscraping with &amp;lsquo;rvest&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Anisha BharathSingh &amp;ldquo;Intro to Latent Variable Modeling&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Apoorva Srinivasan &amp;ldquo;Automating Reports with Gmailr&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Samantha Emanuele &amp;ldquo;How to create a bookdown book in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Joyce Robbins &amp;ldquo;Model Explainability and Interpretability&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Isabel Zimmerman &amp;ldquo;Website Checkout Funnel Analysis in R&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Christina Kim &amp;ldquo;The &amp;lsquo;comorbidity&amp;rsquo; package&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yolanda Barrón &amp;ldquo;Using Google Trends data to assess the impact of COVID-19 on suicidality and suicide - risk factors&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Emily Halford &amp;ldquo;Melvin: a DL-based companion bot&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; MaryLena Bleile  Meetup event</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies NYC networking social event</title>
      <link>/post/networking-social-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/networking-social-event/</guid>
      <description>Though we&amp;rsquo;ll be remote at least through the end of 2020, R-Ladies NYC doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to lose the magic of meetups, where we get to network, socialize, meet new people, and make connections. For our August meetup, we&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting a networking social event where we&amp;rsquo;ll utilize breakout rooms to allow participants to connect (or re-connect) with other members of our community in smaller groups.
This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Authors of &#34;Build a Career in Data Science&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/q-a-authors-build-a-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/q-a-authors-build-a-career/</guid>
      <description>Authors of &amp;ldquo;Build a Career in Data Science&amp;rdquo; Emily Robinson and Jacqueline Nolis will read selections from their book and discuss why they were meaningful and what thinking went into making it. In this session you’ll learn about some of the higher-level thinking that went into designing a book to help people excel in their data science careers, as well as hear stories from Emily and Jacqueline’s pasts that ended up shaping the narrative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leading R Trainings &amp; Prototyping with flexdashboards</title>
      <link>/post/leading-trainings-prototyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/leading-trainings-prototyping/</guid>
      <description>Our very own R-Ladies NYC board members Erin Grand and Kaelen Medeiros will give two short talks this month on leading R trainings for coworkers and flexdashboard!
This event will be hosted over Zoom, and the link will be available on this Meetup page and sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.
Agenda: 7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Leading R Trainings for Coworkers&amp;rdquo; by Erin Grand</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mappy Hour with R-Ladies: Spatial Data Analysis in R</title>
      <link>/post/mappy-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mappy-hour/</guid>
      <description>Our very own Ayanthi Gunawardana and R-Ladies Chicago board member Angela Li join us this month to talk spatial statistics in R!
This event will be hosted over Zoom, and a link will be sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.
Agenda: 7-7:05 pm: R-Ladies NYC Announcements
7:05-7:30: &amp;ldquo;Uncharted Territory: An Introduction to Making Clear and Accurate Maps&amp;rdquo; by Ayanthi Gunawardana
7:30-7:55: &amp;ldquo;How to Be a Resilient Geospatial R useR: First Steps, Learning More, and the Spatial R-Ladies Community&amp;rdquo; by Angela Li</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Blogs</title>
      <link>/post/all-about-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/all-about-blogs/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re so excited to have Angeline, Anisha, Emily, and Sharla talk about their experience with sharing their work through blog posts and twitter! Please email us at nyc@rladies.org with your question(s) for our amazing panelists to address, or submit them below in the comments.
This event will be hosted over Zoom. A link will be sent to all attendees at noon on the day of the event.
Panelist Bios Emily Robinson Emily Robinson is a senior data scientist at Warby Parker, where she works on a centralized team tackling some of the company’s biggest projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for self-guided learning</title>
      <link>/post/resources-for-self-guided-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/resources-for-self-guided-learning/</guid>
      <description>As New Yorkers do all we can to stay well in the times of coronavirus, all of our routines have changed. For some of us, this may mean more time devoted to strengthening our data skills. If this is you, here is a collection of resources that can get you up and running with learning a new skill in R. These were originally compiled for the R-Ladies NYC Code-llaboration Hangout back in January, and are organized by topic: Tidy Tuesday, Building a Package, Building a Website, Time Series Analysis and Everything Else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>timetrackR and gtsummary</title>
      <link>/post/timetrackr-and-gtsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/timetrackr-and-gtsummary/</guid>
      <description>Our speakers for the night will be Jessica Lavery and Margie Hannum from Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center. Jessica will be talking about the timetrackR app. Margie will be discussing the gtsummary package.
Agenda: 6:30-6:55 pm Introductions and Social Time
6:55-7 pm R-Ladies New York Announcements
7-7:10 Sponsor Message from IBM Developer New York
7:10-7:40 It&amp;rsquo;s Time to Shine with timetrackR App, Jessica Lavery
7:40-8:10 Creating publication-ready and reproducible analytical tables with gtsummary, Margie Hannum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Code-llaboration Hangout</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-code-llaboration-hangout/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll kick off the year with a hands-on working session where we&amp;rsquo;ll work together on our own projects or tutorials.
Come in curious about a subject or looking to make progress on a project you&amp;rsquo;re working on!
We&amp;rsquo;ll divide ourselves into groups who&amp;rsquo;ll be working on similar topics, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have prompts and tutorials at hand for those who don&amp;rsquo;t have a particular project in mind.
We believe that by collaborating with other R-Ladies who share your curiosity you’ll get much further than you would at home with google, and that even if you don’t have a set goal you’ll learn through sharing and receiving tips and tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration with Jenny Bryan</title>
      <link>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eoy-celebration-jenny-bryan/</guid>
      <description>To close out 2019, we are thrilled to welcome Jenny Bryan for our R-Ladies New York end-of-year celebration and social! In the potluck tradition of year-end socials past, you are welcome to bring a dessert. Thank you to WarnerMedia for hosting us.
Agenda:
6:30-6:55 pm Introductions and socializing
6:55-7 R-Ladies New York Announcements
7-7:10 Welcome from WarnerMedia
7:10-7:45 Jenny Bryan on debugging and troubleshooting
7:45-8:30 Socializing and networking
Jenny Bryan is a Software Engineer and Data Scientist at RStudio and an Adjunct Professor of Statistics at the University of British Columbia with a Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in healthcare - Ensuring data quality and conducting survival analyses</title>
      <link>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-survival-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>This Meetup features a triple-hitter of talks on R in medicine, biostats and health tech. Each speaker will talk for roughly 20 minutes about the topics below, before and after a half hour of socializing and snacks at Flatiron Health.
Date: Thursday, November 14, 2019
Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm
Speakers: Jacqueline Gutman, Jessica Streeter, Sam Adhikari
Host: Flatiron Health, 233 Spring St
Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Rika Gorn
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-invisible-women/</guid>
      <description>Join us to discuss Invisible Women: Data Bias in a World Designed for Men by Caroline Criado-Pérez
Date: Saturday, November 9, 2019
Time: 2:00pm
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Make Psychological Scales and Data Dictionaries</title>
      <link>/post/scales-dictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scales-dictionaries/</guid>
      <description>Our speakers for the night will be Emily H Ho from Fordham and Samuel Crane from Amplify. Emily will be talking about working with psychological scales in R. Samuel will be talking about building a data dictionary using blogdown.
Date: Tuesday, October 22, 2019
Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm
Speakers: Emily H Ho and Samuel Crane
Host: Amplify, 55 Washington St
Event Organizers: Ludmila Janda, Erin Grand
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Superlearner with sl3 and Parameterizing R Markdown Reports</title>
      <link>/post/superlearner-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/superlearner-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Our speakers for the night will be Elizabeth Mauer and Kat Hoffman from Weill Cornell Medicine. Elizabeth will be talking about parameterized reporting in R Markdown. Kat will be discussing the Superlearner machine learning algorithm using the sl3 package.
Date: Tuesday, September 10, 2019
Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm
Speakers: Elizabeth Mauer and Kat Hoffman
Host: Weill Cornell Medicine, 1300 York Ave
Event Organizers: Elizabeth Sweeney, Alejandra Gerosa
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Career in Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/build-a-career-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/build-a-career-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies NYC is proud and excited that one of our members, Emily Robinson, is co-authoring a book with a fellow R-lady, Jacqueline Nolis! The book, Build a Career in Data Science, is available for pre-order, which comes with online access to all currently available chapters (1-9) access to the rest of the chapters as they come out. This book is a practical guide to preparing for, finding, and excelling in a data science role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to WoRk(flows)</title>
      <link>/post/back-to-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/back-to-workflows/</guid>
      <description>Our speakers David Shilane and Madison Volpe will share tools and workflows to increase productivity and integrate R with Tableau.
Date: Monday, August 26, 2019
Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm
Speakers: David Shilane and Madison Volpe
Host: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center
Event Organizers: Gabriela Hempfling, Alejandra Gerosa
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Join us to discuss Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction by Kieran Healy
Date: Saturday, August 31, 2019
Time: 2:00pm
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hex Sticker Result</title>
      <link>/post/hex-sticker-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hex-sticker-result/</guid>
      <description>The R-Ladies NYC call for a hex sticker design produced three creative and unique submissions. We would like to thank Ayanthi Gunawardana, Kat Hoffman, and Ludmila Janda for their involvement with the R-Ladies NYC community and time spent crafting their designs! Below, each of these R-Ladies shares her inspiration behind her design:
Ayanthi Gunawardana: My goal was the keep the logo and colors as simple as possible to ensure it could be scaled to any size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>Come hang out with R-Ladies at the Royale Bar outdoor patio for an afternoon social full of fun, board games, and splendid R conversation!
Drinks and food will be available for purchase. Collaborative, multi-player and two-player table games will be provided, but feel free to bring your own!
Date: Saturday, July 13, 2019
Time: 2:00pm - 5:00pm
Location: Royale, 157 Loisaida Ave, New York, NY, 10009
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and Fantasy Baseball?</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-and-fantasy-baseball/</guid>
      <description>Thank you so much to Anisha BharathSingh, who originally wrote this post for her blog, found here. We are reposting her post with her consent. If you are an R-Lady interested in writing a blog post or cross-posting a blog post on your own blog, please let us know (via email nyc@rladies.org or via DM on twitter @RLadiesNYC)!
On Thursday, May 23, I attended my first R-Ladies NYC meetup! R-Ladies NYC is an organization that promotes gender diversity amongst the R community by organizing a series of events (including this meetup) to support women who want to learn R or want to share their experiences as R programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-ladies-lighting-talks/</guid>
      <description>We are hosting a very special event - lightning talks from the R-Ladies community! Come out to hear a variety of R &amp;amp; Data Science talks.
Date: Wednesday, June 19, 2019
Time: 6:00pm - 9:00pm
Speakers: A whole lot of R ladies!
Host: OppenheimerFunds
Event Organizers: Brooke Watson, Elizbeth Sweeny
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYR 2019 Speaker Experience and Tips</title>
      <link>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-nyr-conference-tips/</guid>
      <description>The New York R conference attracts a diverse yet technical audience which means the bar is high for all invited speakers. This year, over half the speakers were women, including several R-Ladies NYC members. It was such a fun and good experience that we decided to collaborate and write a blog post to encourage others to speak at conferences and provide some tips.
Speakers: Ludmila Janda, Emily Robinson, Emily Dodwell, Gabriela Hempfling, Elizabeth Sweeny, Soumya Kalra, Brooke Watson, Amanda Dobbyn, Letisha Smith</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Meeting</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-how-not-to-be-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Join us to discuss How Not To Be Wrong by Jordan Ellenberg
Date: Saturday, May 25th, 2019
Time: 2:00pm
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore, 1133 Broadway (between 25th &amp;amp; 26th)
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request for 2019 Lightning Talk Submissions</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talk-submissions-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talk-submissions-request/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies NYC are excited to be hosting an evening of lightning talks on Wednesday June 19! We held this event last year and it was a tremendous success, so we are really excited about the event this year!
Lighting talks are five minute talks. You can talk about anything R, Tech, and/or Data Science related. Looking for ideas? How about talking about a cool package you found, how you use R in your company, a favorite learning resource, your journey into Data Science, or a side project you&amp;rsquo;ve been working on?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request for R-Ladies Logo Submissions</title>
      <link>/post/request-for-r-ladies-logo-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/request-for-r-ladies-logo-submissions/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce that we are holding open submissions for an R-Ladies NYC logo for hex stickers!
Design notes: the R-Ladies font is Open Sans and the colors are #88398a (Purple) &amp;amp; #a7a9ac (Gray), though the logo can use variants of these colors and other colors. Here is the repo for the R-Ladies logo as a reference. Also, the hexSticker package is useful, but you are welcome to use any tool you desire!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Journeys and Fantasy Baseball with R</title>
      <link>/post/getting-into-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-into-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Angeline and Kaelen will discuss their transition into Data Science.
Date: Thursday, May 23rd, 2019
Time: 6:30pm - 8:30pm
Speakers: Angeline Protacio and Kaelen Medeiros
Host: JP Morgan
Event Organizer: Emily Robinson
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/r-package-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-package-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Bring your laptop and come out to our next workshop to learn about building your very own R package!
Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s workshop will focus on R package development from the ground up. We will cover package structure, set-up, creating functions, documentation, testing, dependencies, sharing the package with others, package vignettes, hex stickers, and other methods. An example package will be developed during the workshop so attendees can follow along and create their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Pipelines with Text and Data</title>
      <link>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-pipelines-with-text-and-data/</guid>
      <description>We are excited this month to host two very active R-Ladies from our chapter: Amanda Dobbyn and Maryam Jahanshahi!
See our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details Date Tuesday, February 12, 2019
Time 6:00pm
Host WeWork (205 Hudson S)
Amanda&amp;rsquo;s talk will focus on the package &amp;lsquo;drake&amp;rsquo;. Drake is a package designed to make designing and executing analysis pipelines easier and more reproducible. In this talk Amanda will run through an example of how drake can be used to manage an analysis workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Algorithms to live by</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-algorithms-to-live-by/</guid>
      <description>At our next book club meeting, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss Algorithms to Live By, by Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths.
Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details Please support our wonderful host bookstore, Rizzoli, by ordering the book directly from them through this link
Date Saturday, January 26, 2019
Time 2:00pm
Host Rizzoli Bookstore (1133 Broadway Ave)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git with Joyce</title>
      <link>/post/git-with-joyce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-with-joyce/</guid>
      <description>We are kicking off this year with an introduction to Github by Joyce Robbins.
Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details This is a hands on workshop so please bring your laptop to follow along and please be prompt to make sure the workshop kicks off on time:)
Date: Wednesday, January 9, 2019
Time: 6:30pm
Host: Columbia University (1255 Amsterdam Ave, Room 903)
About Joyce Joyce Robbins, Ph.D., is Lecturer in Discipline in the Statistics Department at Columbia University, where she specializes in data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 End of Year Social</title>
      <link>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</guid>
      <description>Happy Holidays! For the end of the year we are looking to celebrate how far R-Ladies New York has come and thank all of you for your incredible support.
Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details We are doing this potluck style so sign up here to bring something to the party!
Dress in casual or holiday gear - we welcome it all!
Date: Monday, December 10, 2018
Time: 6:30pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility and Communication in R</title>
      <link>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reproducibility-and-communication-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This month it is our pleasure to have Noam Ross and our very own Ludmila Janda present on Reproducibility and Communication in R!
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, November 6, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Host: The New York Times
Agenda: 6:30-6:45pm - General networking
6:45-6:55pm - R-Ladies New York Announcements
6:55-7:25pm - Reproducibility in an Office World: A Brief History of Failures and the Odd Success by Noam Ross</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Computing in R</title>
      <link>/post/parallel-computing-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallel-computing-in-r/</guid>
      <description>We’re excited to host Jared Lander, Chief Data Scientist of Lander Analytics, the organizer of the New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup and the New York R Conference, and author of R for Everyone, to talk about parallel computing in R.
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, November 6, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Speaker: Jared Lander
Host: OppenheimerFunds
Agenda: 6:30-7: Food &amp;amp; networking
7-7:10: Kick-off and announcements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: R Packages by Hadley Wickham</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-r-packages-by-hadley-wickham/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-r-packages-by-hadley-wickham/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for our next book club discussion! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP. Bonus points if you try writing an R package and come to share your experience!
Date: Saturday, October 20, 2018
Time: 2pm
Book: R Packages
Author: Hadley Wickham
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn OOP and discover cool finance packages in R</title>
      <link>/post/learn-oop-and-discover-cool-finance-packages-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learn-oop-and-discover-cool-finance-packages-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Two of our very own R-Ladies NYC board members will be speaking at our September Meetup!
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, September 18, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Speakers: Soumya Kalra and Gabriela Hempfling
Host: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center
Details: For this event we will explore how to do OOP in R and learn the various use cases of the Performance Analytics Package in R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Infrastructure with R</title>
      <link>/post/building-infrastructure-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-infrastructure-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Thursday, August 9, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Speakers: Soumya Kalra and Emily Dodwell
Host: The New York Times
For this event we will explore how to build tools and infrastructure with R.
Agenda: 6:15-6:30pm Introductions and Social
6:30- 6:45 pm NYT announcements (Data, Tech, HR)
6:45-6:55pm R-Ladies New York Announcements
6:55-7:25pm Object Oriented Programming in R
7:25-7:55pm Big Data in R with Small Prototypes: Scaling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning talks roundup</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks-roundup/</guid>
      <description>Our first lightning talk event on Thursday June 14, 2018 at OppenheimerFunds was a huge success! We had a great diversity of speakers from different fields and with different backgrounds who gave talks on a wide variety of R-related topics. Below find a roundup of the lightning talks, including links to slides and videos of each talk. Enjoy!

Breathing New Life into Old PowerPoint Templates: Kelly Dietz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjana Guraziu: An RLady’s First R Conference</title>
      <link>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an-rladys-first-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>The 2018 New York R Conference was my first ever R conference, and it was great. I’ll write here about my experience, with links to resources from the widely varying talks.
First and foremost, I want to thank RLadiesNYC for the scholarship which allowed me to attend the conference. As a self-taught R newbie and incoming grad student, I greatly benefitted from attending this conference, and I so appreciate the opportunity from this great group!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Artificial Unintelligence</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-artificial-unintelligence/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for our next book club discussion! This book club event will include a very special appearance by the author, Meredith Broussard, so don&amp;rsquo;t miss out. Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, July 14, 2018
Time: 11am
Book: Artificial Intelligence: How Computers Misunderstand the World
Author: Meredith Broussard
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks!</title>
      <link>/post/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>We have an awesome lineup of speakers giving lightning talks! These talks are 5 minutes in length on a wide variety of R and data science topics. Come learn from your peers!
Agenda:
6:30-6:55: Food &amp;amp; Networking
6:55-7:00: Introduction by our host
7:00-8:30: Lightning talks
8:30-9:00: Networking
Talks and speakers:
 Using R to Analyze Recruiting Pipelines: Maryam Jahanshahi Freak Your Factors: Luda Janda Cooking Up Statistics: The Science &amp;amp; The Art: Letisha Smith Digital data extraction using R and other tools: Jaya Satagopan Reticulate: An R Interface to Python: Elizabeth Sweeney Who Reads Whom: Text Mining Literary Interviews: Sarah Rankin Teaching the Tidyverse to Coworkers: Erin Grand InteRactive: how to make your reports more engaging with R &amp;amp; Plotly: Gulya Radjapova Debugging Data in R: Hannah Flaherty Sum of Nothing: R, Python pandas, and the different ways to do math with missing data: Christine Zhang Non-Representative Polls: Jennifer Kanjana Breathing New Life into Old PowerPoint Templates: Kelly Dietz The Stories behind Missing Data: Policy and Practice in Social Services: Rika Gorn Cracking the Data Science Interview: Learning from Both Sides of the Interview Table: Catherine Zhou  Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Shiny Apps using NBA data</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-shiny-apps-using-nba-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-shiny-apps-using-nba-data/</guid>
      <description>Come out for our May event for a tutorial on Shiny! Julia Wrobel, a PhD candidate in biostatistics at Columbia University, will be teaching us to make and deploy Shiny apps using NBA data.
The materials for this talk can be found on Julia&amp;rsquo;s website.
Bring your laptops so that you can code as you go!
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, May 8, 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Storytelling with Data</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-storytelling-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-storytelling-with-data/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for our next book club discussion! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, April 28, 2018
Time: 3pm
Book: STORYTELLING WITH DATA: A DATA VISUALIZATION GUIDE FOR BUSINESS PROFESSIONALS
Author: Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy evaluation: Programming with ggplot2 and dplyr</title>
      <link>/post/tidy-evaluation-programming-with-ggplot2-and-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidy-evaluation-programming-with-ggplot2-and-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>For this month&amp;rsquo;s meetup we have a very special guest : Hadley Wickham!
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Thursday, April 19, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Speaker: Hadley Wickham
Host: Two Sigma</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in R</title>
      <link>/post/scraping-javascript-websites-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scraping-javascript-websites-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Background: remixing packages in RJavascript webscraping in RDownload PhantomJS using homebrewWriting scrape.jsScraping TheRapBoard.comExtracting audio filesDownloading mp3sOrganizing an R packageConverting mp3s to wavsCleaning up and filtering .wav file namesTidying file namesRenaming file paths from within RRemixing the beep() functionWrapping it all into a packageMaintaining an open source package in RBackground: remixing packages in ROpen source software is made for remixing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelization of Simulations with the foreach Package and Missing Data in R</title>
      <link>/post/parallelization-foreach-and-missing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallelization-foreach-and-missing-data/</guid>
      <description>Come out to our March event to hear talks from two great R Ladies!
First we&amp;rsquo;ll learn about parallelization of simulations with the foreach R package, with applications to progression free survival assessed using electronic health records. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll get an introduction to methods for handling missing data in R.
Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, March 20, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Speakers: Elizabeth Sweeney and Mine Dogucu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating websites in R</title>
      <link>/post/creating-websites-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-websites-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Ever wanted to create a blog or website to share your work or ideas? Join us for a tutorial on creating websites in R! Emily Zabor will cover the basics of creating a website or blog in R. After the tutorial, Daniela Vazquez of R Ladies Buenos Aires and Montevideo, will give us a one-year update on her transition to a data science career. Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Functional Programming with Purrr</title>
      <link>/post/workshop-functional-programming-with-purrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workshop-functional-programming-with-purrr/</guid>
      <description>Join us for our first R Ladies NYC event of 2018!
Joyce Robbins presents a workshop on the purrr package, a complete and coherent packae for working with functions and vectors in R. Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Joyce&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo for this talk can be found here.
Date: Wednesday, January 10, 2018
Time: 6:30pm
Instructor: Joyce Robbins
Host: Schapiro Center Columbia University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jasmine Williams: My first step to healing from WISDOM (Women in Stats, Data Science, and Omics)</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-step-to-healing-from-wisdom-women-in-stats-data-science-and-omics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-step-to-healing-from-wisdom-women-in-stats-data-science-and-omics/</guid>
      <description>As it grew nearer to the fall season my heart and mind grew heavier. This was the first birthday and holiday gatherings without grandma. I became distant from everything outside of my family and work, and knew I had to get out of this emotional funk. The 2017 Women in Statistics and Data Science conference brought together hundreds of data scientists and statisticians from all walks of life in an intimate setting to share their personal and professional experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon!</title>
      <link>/post/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Stay tuned in 2018 for the R-Ladies NYC blog, which will feature guest bloggers from the R-Ladies NYC community. Interested in writing a blog post? Contact us at nyc@rladies.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Everybody Lies</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-everybody-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-everybody-lies/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for our first book club discussion of 2018! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, January 20, 2018
Time: 3pm
Book: Everybody Lies: Big Data, New Data, and What the Internet Can Tell Us About Who We Really Are
Author: Seth Stephens-Davidowitz
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in the World of Education</title>
      <link>/post/r-in-the-world-of-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-in-the-world-of-education/</guid>
      <description>Join us for our last event of 2017!
Erin Grand will speak about how she uses R in the World of Eduction. Visit our Meetup for more details and to RSVP.
Erin&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo for this event can be found here.
Date: Tuesday, December 12, 2017
Time: 6:30pm
Speaker: Erin Grand
Host: AT&amp;amp;T NYC Data Science Research Center</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Dive Night with Data for Democracy</title>
      <link>/post/data-dive-night-with-data-for-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-dive-night-with-data-for-democracy/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get together with our laptops and R skills and code to continue to explore Medicare spending data. Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, October 24, 2017
Time: 6:30pm
Host: Quartet Health</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Truth or Truthiness</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-truth-or-truthiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-truth-or-truthiness/</guid>
      <description>Come join us for a discussion for our next book club discussion! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, September 30, 2017
Time: 12pm
Book: Truth or Truthiness: Distinguishing Fact from Fiction by Learning to Think Like a Data Scientist
Author: Howard Wainer
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization Workshop, Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/data-visualization-workshop-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-visualization-workshop-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Joyce Robbins presents a workshop on creating heatmaps in R, and other more general data visualization tips and tricks. Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Joyce&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo for this talk can be found here.
Date: Thursday, August 17, 2017
Time: 7pm
Instructor: Joyce Robbins
Host: Byte Academy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social!</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a break from the heat and our desks for an R-Ladies summer social event! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, July 8, 2017
Time: 2pm
Where: Blue Ribbon Sushi Izakaya</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Weapons of Math Destruction</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-weapons-of-math-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-weapons-of-math-destruction/</guid>
      <description>Come join us for a discussion for our next book club discussion! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, June 17, 2017
Time: 11am
Book: Weapons of Math Destruction: How Big Data Increases Inequality and Threatens Democracy
Author: Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour of R in Peer to Peer Lending</title>
      <link>/post/tour-of-r-in-peer-to-peer-lending/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tour-of-r-in-peer-to-peer-lending/</guid>
      <description>Catherine Pargeter speaks about how Orchard Platform, a fintech company, uses R. Visit our Meetup for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, April 18, 2017
Time: 6:30pm
Speaker: Catherine Pargeter
Host: Orchard Platform</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book club: Dear Data</title>
      <link>/post/book-club-dear-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/book-club-dear-data/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for our inaugural book club event! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, March 11, 2017
Time: 11am
Book: Dear Data
Authors: Giorgia Lupi and Stefanie Posavec
Host: Rizzoli Bookstore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Focus on Health</title>
      <link>/post/a-focus-on-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-focus-on-health/</guid>
      <description>Elena Colicino and Daniela Vazquez speak about how they use R. Vist our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Tuesday, February 21, 2017
Time: 6:30pm
Speakers: Elena Colicino and Daniela Vazquez
Host: Flatiron Health</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching R-Ladies NYC!</title>
      <link>/post/launching-r-ladies-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/launching-r-ladies-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Come meet other local R-Ladies and hear Carissa Shafto speak about her use of R for data science at the Galen College of Nursing. Vist our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Monday, November 21, 2016
Time: 6:15pm
Speaker: Carissa Shafto
Host: RGGI Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2017-02-21-a-focus-on-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-02-21-a-focus-on-health/</guid>
      <description>A Focus on Health/*! jQuery v1.11.3 | (c) 2005, 2015 jQuery Foundation, Inc. | jquery.org/license */!function(a,b){&#34;object&#34;==typeof module&amp;&amp;&#34;object&#34;==typeof module.exports?module.exports=a.document?b(a,!0):function(a){if(!a.document)throw new Error(&#34;jQuery requires a window with a document&#34;);return b(a)}:b(a)}(&#34;undefined&#34;!=typeof window?window:this,function(a,b){var c=[],d=c.slice,e=c.concat,f=c.push,g=c.indexOf,h={},i=h.toString,j=h.hasOwnProperty,k={},l=&#34;1.11.3&#34;,m=function(a,b){return new m.fn.init(a,b)},n=/^[\s\uFEFF\xA0]+|[\s\uFEFF\xA0]+$/g,o=/^-ms-/,p=/-([\da-z])/gi,q=function(a,b){return b.toUpperCase()};m.fn=m.prototype={jquery:l,constructor:m,selector:&#34;&#34;,length:0,toArray:function(){return d.call(this)},get:function(a){return null!=a?0a?this[a+this.length]:this[a]:d.call(this)},pushStack:function(a){var b=m.merge(this.constructor(),a);return b.prevObject=this,b.context=this.context,b},each:function(a,b){return m.each(this,a,b)},map:function(a){return this.pushStack(m.map(this,function(b,c){return a.call(b,c,b)}))},slice:function(){return this.pushStack(d.apply(this,arguments))},first:function(){return this.eq(0)},last:function(){return this.eq(-1)},eq:function(a){var b=this.length,c=+a+(0a?b:0);return this.pushStack(c=0&amp;&amp;bc?[this[c]]:[])},end:function(){return this.prevObject||this.constructor(null)},push:f,sort:c.sort,splice:c.splice},m.extend=m.fn.extend=function(){var a,b,c,d,e,f,g=arguments[0]||{},h=1,i=arguments.length,j=!1;for(&#34;boolean&#34;==typeof g&amp;&amp;(j=g,g=arguments[h]||{},h++),&#34;object&#34;==typeof g||m.isFunction(g)||(g={}),h===i&amp;&amp;(g=this,h--);ih;h++)if(null!=(e=arguments[h]))for(d in e)a=g[d],c=e[d],g!==c&amp;&amp;(j&amp;&amp;c&amp;&amp;(m.isPlainObject(c)||(b=m.isArray(c)))?(b?(b=!1,f=a&amp;&amp;m.isArray(a)?a:[]):f=a&amp;&amp;m.isPlainObject(a)?a:{},g[d]=m.extend(j,f,c)):void 0!==c&amp;&amp;(g[d]=c));return g},m.extend({expando:&#34;jQuery&#34;+(l+Math.random()).replace(/\D/g,&#34;&#34;),isReady:!0,error:function(a){throw new Error(a)},noop:function(){},isFunction:function(a){return&#34;function&#34;===m.type(a)},isArray:Array.isArray||function(a){return&#34;array&#34;===m.type(a)},isWindow:function(a){return null!=a&amp;&amp;a==a.window},isNumeric:function(a){return!m.isArray(a)&amp;&amp;a-parseFloat(a)+1=0},isEmptyObject:function(a){var b;for(b in a)return!1;return!0},isPlainObject:function(a){var b;if(!a||&#34;object&#34;!==m.type(a)||a.nodeType||m.isWindow(a))return!1;try{if(a.constructor&amp;&amp;!j.call(a,&#34;constructor&#34;)&amp;&amp;!j.call(a.constructor.prototype,&#34;isPrototypeOf&#34;))return!1}catch(c){return!1}if(k.ownLast)for(b in a)return j.call(a,b);for(b in a);return void 0===b||j.call(a,b)},type:function(a){return null==a?a+&#34;&#34;:&#34;object&#34;==typeof a||&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-17-getting-into-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-17-getting-into-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Data Science Journeys and Fantasy Baseball with R/*! jQuery v1.11.3 | (c) 2005, 2015 jQuery Foundation, Inc. | jquery.org/license */!function(a,b){&#34;object&#34;==typeof module&amp;&amp;&#34;object&#34;==typeof module.exports?module.exports=a.document?b(a,!0):function(a){if(!a.document)throw new Error(&#34;jQuery requires a window with a document&#34;);return b(a)}:b(a)}(&#34;undefined&#34;!=typeof window?window:this,function(a,b){var c=[],d=c.slice,e=c.concat,f=c.push,g=c.indexOf,h={},i=h.toString,j=h.hasOwnProperty,k={},l=&#34;1.11.3&#34;,m=function(a,b){return new m.fn.init(a,b)},n=/^[\s\uFEFF\xA0]+|[\s\uFEFF\xA0]+$/g,o=/^-ms-/,p=/-([\da-z])/gi,q=function(a,b){return b.toUpperCase()};m.fn=m.prototype={jquery:l,constructor:m,selector:&#34;&#34;,length:0,toArray:function(){return d.call(this)},get:function(a){return null!=a?0a?this[a+this.length]:this[a]:d.call(this)},pushStack:function(a){var b=m.merge(this.constructor(),a);return b.prevObject=this,b.context=this.context,b},each:function(a,b){return m.each(this,a,b)},map:function(a){return this.pushStack(m.map(this,function(b,c){return a.call(b,c,b)}))},slice:function(){return this.pushStack(d.apply(this,arguments))},first:function(){return this.eq(0)},last:function(){return this.eq(-1)},eq:function(a){var b=this.length,c=+a+(0a?b:0);return this.pushStack(c=0&amp;&amp;bc?[this[c]]:[])},end:function(){return this.prevObject||this.constructor(null)},push:f,sort:c.sort,splice:c.splice},m.extend=m.fn.extend=function(){var a,b,c,d,e,f,g=arguments[0]||{},h=1,i=arguments.length,j=!1;for(&#34;boolean&#34;==typeof g&amp;&amp;(j=g,g=arguments[h]||{},h++),&#34;object&#34;==typeof g||m.isFunction(g)||(g={}),h===i&amp;&amp;(g=this,h--);ih;h++)if(null!=(e=arguments[h]))for(d in e)a=g[d],c=e[d],g!==c&amp;&amp;(j&amp;&amp;c&amp;&amp;(m.isPlainObject(c)||(b=m.isArray(c)))?(b?(b=!1,f=a&amp;&amp;m.isArray(a)?a:[]):f=a&amp;&amp;m.isPlainObject(a)?a:{},g[d]=m.extend(j,f,c)):void 0!==c&amp;&amp;(g[d]=c));return g},m.extend({expando:&#34;jQuery&#34;+(l+Math.random()).replace(/\D/g,&#34;&#34;),isReady:!0,error:function(a){throw new Error(a)},noop:function(){},isFunction:function(a){return&#34;function&#34;===m.type(a)},isArray:Array.isArray||function(a){return&#34;array&#34;===m.type(a)},isWindow:function(a){return null!=a&amp;&amp;a==a.window},isNumeric:function(a){return!m.isArray(a)&amp;&amp;a-parseFloat(a)+1=0},isEmptyObject:function(a){var b;for(b in a)return!1;return!0},isPlainObject:function(a){var b;if(!a||&#34;object&#34;!==m.type(a)||a.nodeType||m.isWindow(a))return!1;try{if(a.constructor&amp;&amp;!j.call(a,&#34;constructor&#34;)&amp;&amp;!j.call(a.constructor.prototype,&#34;isPrototypeOf&#34;))return!1}catch(c){return!1}if(k.ownLast)for(b in a)return j.call(a,b);for(b in a);return void 0===b||j.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/background-remixing-packages-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/background-remixing-packages-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.sourceCode { white-space: pre-wrap; }code.sourceCode  span { text-indent: -5em; padding-left: 5em; }}pre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/javascript-webscraping-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/javascript-webscraping-in-r/</guid>
      <description>2 Javascript webscraping in R | Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.sourceCode { white-space: pre-wrap; }code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/maintaining-an-open-source-package-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/maintaining-an-open-source-package-in-r/</guid>
      <description>6 Maintaining an open source package in R | Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/organizing-an-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/organizing-an-r-package/</guid>
      <description>3 Organizing an R package | Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.sourceCode { white-space: pre-wrap; }code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/remixing-the-beep-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/remixing-the-beep-function/</guid>
      <description>4 Remixing the beep() function | Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.sourceCode { white-space: pre-wrap; }code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/_book/wrapping-it-all-into-a-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/_book/wrapping-it-all-into-a-package/</guid>
      <description>5 Wrapping it all into a package | Brooke Watson: Scraping Javascript websites in Rcode.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; }code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; }code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; }.sourceCode { overflow: visible; }code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; }pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; }@media screen {div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; }}@media print {code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>