<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on R-Ladies NYC</title>
    <link>/categories/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on R-Ladies NYC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 R-Ladies NYC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration for Women and Gender Minorities</title>
      <link>/post/eoy-celebration-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eoy-celebration-2022/</guid>
      <description>Happy Holidays! Come celebrate how far R-Ladies New York has come this year at this fun, end-of-the-year social at Whiskey Ward. This event will be in-person, and a great gathering to close out our year!
We want to thank you all for your incredible support and for being part of the R-Ladies community. We hope to see you there!
Drinks will be available for purchase. Dress in casual or holiday gear - we welcome it all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>Come hang out with R-Ladies at the Lucky backyard for an evening social full of fun and splendid R conversation!
Drinks will be available for purchase. But you are also welcome to bring in your own food!
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Year Celebration for Women and Gender Minorities</title>
      <link>/post/eoy-celebration-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eoy-celebration-2021/</guid>
      <description>[Please note: At the request of members of our community for an R-Ladies space exclusively for minority genders, this event is limited to those who identify as such (including but not limited to women, trans men, non-binary, and gender nonconforming individuals). Male allies have been great supporters of our chapter and the R-Ladies mission to promote gender diversity in the R Community &amp;ndash; for which we are grateful! &amp;ndash; and we believe the best way male allies can support us this month is by honoring the need for and benefit of such a space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>Come hang out with R-Ladies at the Royale Bar outdoor patio for an afternoon social full of fun, board games, and splendid R conversation!
Drinks and food will be available for purchase. Collaborative, multi-player and two-player table games will be provided, but feel free to bring your own!
Date: Saturday, July 13, 2019
Time: 2:00pm - 5:00pm
Location: Royale, 157 Loisaida Ave, New York, NY, 10009
Meetup page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 End of Year Social</title>
      <link>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-end-of-year-social/</guid>
      <description>Happy Holidays! For the end of the year we are looking to celebrate how far R-Ladies New York has come and thank all of you for your incredible support.
Visit our Meetup page to RSVP.
Details We are doing this potluck style so sign up here to bring something to the party!
Dress in casual or holiday gear - we welcome it all!
Date: Monday, December 10, 2018
Time: 6:30pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Social!</title>
      <link>/post/summer-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer-social/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a break from the heat and our desks for an R-Ladies summer social event! Visit our Meetup page for more details and to RSVP.
Date: Saturday, July 8, 2017
Time: 2pm
Where: Blue Ribbon Sushi Izakaya</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>